<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: dell | Blog In Isolation]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/categories/dell/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T20:07:32+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy C]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[credit where credit is due]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/11/15/credit-where-credit-is-due/"/>
    <updated>2005-11-15T05:54:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/11/15/credit-where-credit-is-due</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In an earlier
<a href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/10/29/beware-of-shopping-at-dell-computers/">post</a>,
I moaned about Dell's opaque pricing model on their UK Web site.
However, people (especially me) are very quick to moan and complain
but often slow to give thanks and appreciation.</p>

<p>I subsequently contacted Dell Customer Services to complain that the
invoice was for a different amount agreed on the phone (strong case)
and the fact I discovered that I could configure an identical PC for
an even lower price (weaker argument).</p>

<p>The lady from Dell Customer Services initially suggested that I cancel
the original order and simply place another order online at the lower
price. I pointed out that this was a little silly as it would mean
cancelling an order for one computer and adding a new order for a
brand new computer with the identical specification.</p>

<p>In any event, it transpired that the PC had already been dispatched
from Dell to the courier company, so I would have to call a different
department 'Pre Sales Delivery' to cancel the order.</p>

<p>The gentleman in 'Pre Sales Delivery' was more helpful and agreed that
cancelling the current order was ludicrous. He offered me a
All-In-One-Printer free of charge. While this was a nice gesture, I
told him I already had a printer. He then offered me a digital camera
free of charge but I already had one of those too. I stood my ground
and insisted on the refund and he finally agreed.</p>

<p>The gentleman also gave me his direct email and the name of his
supervisor in case of any subsequent issues with the refund. So, I am
pleased to say that Dell honoured the lowest price for the PC. It was
inconvenient, took a little persistence and a few phone calls but for
54GBP it was well worth it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beware of shopping at Dell computers]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/10/29/beware-of-shopping-at-dell-computers/"/>
    <updated>2005-10-29T20:31:12+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/10/29/beware-of-shopping-at-dell-computers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Imagine walking into a department store to buy a TV. You weigh up all
the possible options and decide which model you want. The price of
this TV is 457GBP. The assistant says 'That will be 457 pounds, Sir'
as she takes the credit card payment and arranges delivery for next
week.</p>

<p>You then happen to go up to the second floor and see the identical TV
for 422GBP. That's 35GBP cheaper than what you've just paid. You go
back to the assistant who sold you the goods to query this difference
in the price. Unfortunately, the assistant is now on her lunch break
but you are promised that she will call you back. She doesn't.</p>

<p>You then leave the department store via the ground floor where you see
the identical TV priced at 565GBP.</p>

<p>You arrive home and just happen to check the credit card receipt. The
amount debited is 476GBP instead of 457GBP. Silly you; you should have
checked the amount more carefully at the time. You call the department
store to complain. The customer services manager you need to speak to
is on a break but he will call you back immediately. He doesn't.</p>

<p>Well that is how online shopping for a Dell computer works. There are
many different possible ways to configure the identical specification
for a desktop PC and get a completely different price ranging from
422GBP to 565GBP. This difference appears to depend on which path
(Offers page, Dimension page) you followed through the Dell web site
(and which E-Code is listed) when you added and subtracted the various
possible options to configure the final system.</p>

<p>So, if you are thinking of buying a computer from Dell, always compare
every conceivable way of configuring the final system before placing
the order. Always order on the Internet once you are confident you
have obtained the cheapest price. Never order on the telephone from a
human being. I was given one price on the telephone and when the
invoice arrived via email, a higher price was listed.</p>

<p>Alternatively, it might be just simpler to buy your computer
elsewhere.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
