<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: blogging | Blog In Isolation]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/categories/blogging/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T20:07:32+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy C]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[the awkward second post]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/the-awkward-second-post/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-14T19:07:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/the-awkward-second-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Octopress is great</p>

<ul>
<li>Uses Google to provide site search</li>
<li>Archives builtin</li>
<li>Tag support</li>
<li>Draft posts</li>
<li>Local preview</li>
<li>Markdown markup</li>
<li>Google+, Disqus, Google Analytics support</li>
<li>Incremental deployment</li>
<li>Deployment to Amazon S3</li>
<li>Fast as lightning</li>
</ul>


<p>Wish I'd bitten the bullet earlier.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-14T16:49:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my first post in Octopress.</p>

<p>The text uses <em>Markdown</em> which is <strong>marvellous</strong>.</p>

<p>My favourite blogging platforms are:</p>

<ul>
<li>Octopress</li>
<li>Habari</li>
<li>Drupal</li>
<li>WordPress</li>
</ul>


<p>The <a href="http://bbc.co.uk">BBC</a> is a popular Web site.</p>

<p>End of message.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[migration plan]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/migration-plan/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-14T15:55:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/migration-plan</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Loose thoughts on the plan of attack for the blog migration:</p>

<ol>
<li>Install Octopress locally</li>
<li>Configure S3 and install a dummy Web site.</li>
<li>Use's3cmd' to upload test site to Amazon S3</li>
<li>Test incremental uploads. This is a firm requirement.</li>
<li>Full database backup of existing Drupal blog</li>
<li>Take backup of Drupal installation (additional modules, scripts).</li>
<li>Install vanilla Drupal 7 locally.</li>
<li>Install copy of the existing Dupal blog in local version (overwrite database ?).</li>
<li>Use the Drupal to Octopress migration script. This extracts nodes from the database and creates Markdown files for each post, This script is probably for Drupal 6 so some tweaks (major rewrite) may be needed for bleeding edge Drupal 7. URL aliasing is supposedly supported.</li>
<li>Test the various elements in the <a href="http://nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/blog-migration-checklist">checklist</a>. Disqus comments need the correct domain name so will have to come last.</li>
<li>Configure a redirect from 'nbrightside.com' to the Amazon URL. I can see trouble and lots of Googl'ing here.</li>
<li>Place source code (Markdown posts) into GitHub repository.</li>
<li>Put kettle on.</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[blog migration checklist]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/blog-migration/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-14T15:45:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/blog-migration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am a veteran of blog migrations with the scars to prove it. Here is a handy 'cut out and keep' checklist of the important things I normally forget:</p>

<ul>
<li>Permalink structure. Try to preserve the existing permalink structure to save hours of pain. This is particularly important when using Disqus (although there is a URL migration utility for Disqus).</li>
<li>Typically, I like to have 'Archives', 'About' and a 'Contact' page.</li>
<li>Tag support including a 'Tags' page.</li>
<li>Images. I have learned to upload all photos and screenshots to PicasaWeb and intentionally de-couple images from the blog platform.</li>
<li>Sitemap support. Helps search engines index the site.</li>
<li>RSS/Atom support . Previously I have always used Feedburner (although I may follow Google's example and sever this dependency) and simply use the native feed. Less is more.</li>
<li>Comments. Static site generators are slightly limited here (compared with proper blogging platforms) so I guess I will continue to use Disqus. Mind you, for the number of comments versus spam, I may also dispense with comments and invite people to use Google+ or identi.ca.</li>
<li>Themes. It would be desirable to be able to change themes to avoid having the same look and feel and every other Octopress blog.</li>
</ul>


<p>Please feel free to add your own tips in the comments.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Autumn migration]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/autumn-migration/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-14T14:45:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/autumn-migration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My Web hosting package (provided by Bluehost) expires in October. As
this blog is essentially dead (the last post was a one-liner 8 months
ago), the sensible and logical thing to do would be to kill the blog
and save £5 a month.</p>

<p>Originally I
<a href="http://nbrightside.com/blog/2006/10/24/new-dawn-fades">purchased</a> the
domain name 'nbrightside.com' and the Web hosting for a couple of
reasons:</p>

<ul>
<li>I wanted to use self hosted WordPress without some of the restrictions imposed by WordPress.com</li>
<li>I wanted to play with some of the packaged applications offered by Bluehost.</li>
<li>I wanted access to a Linux environment, mainly to build, install, experiment with various open source software tools and packages which needed a LAMP stack.</li>
</ul>


<p>It's really questionable whether I need to maintain this Web presence
but, on balance, I'd like to keep the site alive for a little longer.</p>

<p>WordPress, Drupal, Habari et al are all fantastic blogging platforms
but rather overkill for this simple, single user blog. For a while, I
have been fascinated and trying to resist the temptation of the
simplicity and power of static Web site generators like
<a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a> and
<a href="http://hyde.github.com/">Hyde</a>.</p>

<p>Last year, I even ported the complete contents of this Drupal 7 blog
to a locally installed version of Hyde and labouriously fixed up lots
of hyperlinks just so the Markdown looked neater.</p>

<p>The completely logical and sensible decision would be to simply
resurrect this Hyde environment, re-sync the last couple of one liner
blog posts, configure a automatic redirect and use rsync to upload
this site to some alternative, cheaper (or free) Web hosting.</p>

<p>So, I have decided to use <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> and
<a href="http://aws.typepad.com/aws/2011/02/host-your-static-website-on-amazon-s3.html">Amazon
S3</a>
to host this humble, annually updated blog in the future. I may be
able to reuse some of the Hyde content with judicious use of sed to
convert the meta data in the header sections or I may just start
afresh.</p>

<p>No - I am no mad.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
