<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: uk | Blog In Isolation]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/categories/uk/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T20:07:32+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy C]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[humour on BBC breakfast]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/07/21/humour-bbc-breakfast/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-21T09:23:58+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/07/21/humour-bbc-breakfast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>BBC Breakfast ran a story this morning about the sale of
<a href="http://www.woodlands.co.uk/buying-a-wood/">woodlands</a>. The gentlemen
responsible for selling woodlands was quite a comedian. He started his
act with:</p>

<blockquote><p>'In these difficult economic times, people are looking to invest in
woodlands to hedge their bets...'</p></blockquote>

<p>and then, referring to the potential investment opportunity and
without a glimmer of a smile, he delivered the immaculate line</p>

<blockquote><p>'In a few years time, once the wood has matured, people will see
that you can get income from trees'.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[farewell Paul Scholes]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/05/31/farewell-paul-scholes/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-31T09:11:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/05/31/farewell-paul-scholes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/RD2bDI-AOBjwHYPgXVHS1w?feat=embedwebsite"><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-queZ1d_BoUs/TeSv7gEeUII/AAAAAAAABvE/7vhA7va4eyA/s800/Paul-Scholes-Manchester-United-Barcelona-Cham_2602915.jpg"
height="298" width="218"></a></p>

<p>One of my favourite United players - for his sublime skills on the
pitch and the modest, understated way he conducted himself off
it. Thanks for all the memories, Paul.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[C grade student]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/04/24/c-grade-student/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-24T13:13:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/04/24/c-grade-student</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Chatting with a good friend over dinner last night, he recounted how
his son ambushed him late one Sunday night with some economics
homework that he'd somehow manage to overlook and which simply had to
be submitted the following morning.</p>

<p>Annoyed, and after dispensing a severe bollocking, he reluctantly sat
down and gave his son some lengthy help with the complex and thorny
topic of</p>

<blockquote><p>'How does monetary policy affect the economy ?'</p></blockquote>

<p>A week later, his son mumbled 'Oh yeah - I got that Eco essay back
today and got a 'C' for it'.</p>

<p>My friend has a first class honours degree in Economics from the
University of Warwick, has spent 26 years working in finance and
banking and is currently a senior economic analyst for the leading
fund manager, Gartmore.</p>

<p>My - how we laughed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[exciting times]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/03/03/exciting-times/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-03T10:07:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/03/03/exciting-times</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>These are indeed exciting times in the Brightside household:</p>

<ul>
<li>Norma Jeane will be taking part in the 125th Lawn Tennis
Championships to be held at
<a href="http://nbrightside.com/blog/2008/07/06/wimbledon-match-report">Wimbledon</a>
between 20 June and 3 July. Her precise role isn't known yet but may
include 'Waiting On (Silver Service)' - fawning over loud,
overbearing sales people out on a corporate jolly, 'Bar staff'
(serving jugs of Pimms to middle aged Daily Mail readers) or
tantalisingly, 'Courtesy car driver' (ferrying a morose
<a href="http://nbrightside.com/blog/2009/09/09/inside-the-mind-of-andy-murray">Andy Murray</a>
around). This represents a rapid promotion from her initial
placement two years ago, where she started out on 'Litter collection
surrounding courts 10 and 11' before being promoted to 'Housekeeping
duties' or, as she so eloquently put it - 'Cleaning the bogs'.</li>
<li>Norma will be visiting Holloway prison in April. She claims this is
part of her District Nursing course but I have my doubts. She seems
to be watching a lot of those legal dramas recently and taking
copious notes.</li>
<li>Norman Junior III is recuperating from fracturing his right arm for
the second time. Note to self - any activity containing the word
'roller' that takes place on a concrete road is potentially
hazardous. He is soldiering on quite well and only needs assistance
with his socks. He has subsequently changed his XBox nickname to
'OneArmedBandit' and is experimenting using his toes to manipulate
the controller.</li>
<li>I had a brush with West Midlands traffic police last week in
Solihull after daring to consult a old fashioned map while
driving. After 15 minutes of being patronised by a fascist pig and
being forced to beg and scrape on bended knee, I managed to escape
with a verbal warning instead of the threatened '6 point penalty for
careless driving'. However, I am still puzzling over the 'correct'
answer to the copper's deep, probing question: 'Sir, please could
you tell me why were you travelling at 25 miles per hour in a 30
zone ?'</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[why Arsenal lost the Carling Cup]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/03/01/why-arsenal-lost-carling-cup/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-01T11:42:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/03/01/why-arsenal-lost-carling-cup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I heard that Arsenal were busy making plans for their injured and
oh so inspirational captain, Cesc Fabregas, to hoist the trophy aloft
and end 6 barren years without a sniff of a trophy, I had a horrible
feeling it might end that way.</p>

<p>Can you imagine the suspended United captain, a grey suited Roy Keane,
doing that back in 1999 ? Can you even imagine Ferguson even
contemplating that option for just a second ? No. Neither can I.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
