<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: software | Blog In Isolation]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/categories/software/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T20:07:32+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy C]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Music - available by 2017]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/07/26/google-music-available-2017/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-26T11:07:05+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/07/26/google-music-available-2017</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks ago, I signed up for a invitation to Google Music. The
service is only available in the US but, by a lucky chance of fate, I
just happened to be connected to my corporate VPN so I was successful
and an invitation duly arrived in my Inbox.</p>

<p>Initially, the Google Music Manager software didn't support Linux. Nor
was the Ogg Vorbis audio format supported so I didn't pursue it any
further as both of these were show stoppers for me. I don't intend
re-ripping my entire music collection to MP3 format.</p>

<p>However, last week, Google released a Linux version of Music Manager
and added
'<a href="http://www.google.com/support/music/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;answer=1100462&amp;topic=1100183">support</a>'
for Ogg format audio files. The 'support' for the Ogg format is
slightly strange - Ogg audio files will be transcoded back to 320kps
MP3 files which represents a conversion from one lossy format to
another lossy format. Hopefully, in the longer term, there will be
true native support for Ogg.</p>

<p>Anyway, I downloaded the Music Manager software and started uploading
my music collection mainly so I could listen to music on my netbook
which currently runs <a href="http://chromeos.hexxeh.net/">Chromium OS</a>.</p>

<p>I started the upload 2 days ago and it's been running during the
day. So far, it has managed to upload 505 songs out of a total 1,880
so it's not exactly a speedy process.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[first and last and always - Google Reader]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/01/05/first-and-last-and-always-google-reader/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-05T15:21:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/01/05/first-and-last-and-always-google-reader</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Steve Rubel has
<a href="http://www.steverubel.com/a-return-to-feed-reading-tops-my-2011-tech-re">resolved</a>
to return to feed reading in 2011.</p>

<p>However, I have been using Google Reader since 2007 and use it daily
to catch up with the tech and sports news in addition to my favourite
blogs. I honestly can't imagine life without it. I was also interested
by a recent
<a href="http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/google-reader-bookmarking-service/">article</a>
(prompted by the demise of delicio.us) that described the use of
Google Reader as a bookmarking service.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox and Thunderbird]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/08/24/firefox-and-thunderbird/"/>
    <updated>2005-08-24T03:40:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/08/24/firefox-and-thunderbird</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well I was finally forced to join the masses and download
<a href="http://www.mozilla.com/firefox/">Firefox</a> and ditch Internet
Explorer.  Yes - my nickname is 'Johnny Come Lately'.</p>

<p>I had been aware of the Firefox browser for a while but my previous
experience was with a very early version of Mozilla that had a few
problems with a couple of the Web sites I was using at the time.</p>

<p>The final straw came that pushed me over the edge was when my children
downloaded some invasive spyware that commandeered the Web browser and
implanted a 'Web Search' toolbar. As you can not deconfigure this
toolbar without completely removing the product, I found myself
uninstalling it, my kids would reinstall it for some whizzy colourful
cursors. Repeat ad infinitum. Life is simply too short.</p>

<p>The immediate benefit of Firefox is the tabbed browsing which lets you
keep multiple Web sites open and visible at the same time. After you
have used this feature for a while, it is indispensible and you wonder
how you ever lived without it.</p>

<p>Then I experimented with RSS feeds from the BBC and elsewhere. Instead
of having to periodically check a range of Web sites for any new
content, I wanted automatic notification of when new content was
available. However, while the 'Live bookmarks' feature in Firefox was
pretty good, I really wanted something like a pseudo newsgroup that
would list new articles on a Website just like articles in a newsgroup.
So, I downloaded <a href="http://www.mozilla.com/thunderbird/">Thunderbird</a>
which seamlessly and painlessly converted all my email messages and
contacts from Outlook Express and I was finished.</p>

<p>I have been using Firefox for a week now and so far, the only Web sites
that I have encountered problems with is Sony's SonicStage download page
(which insists on Microsoft Internet Explorer 5.0) and Blueyonder's
selfcare home page (which is gloriously blank). However, this probably
says more about the authors of these Web sites rather than any
deficiencies in Firefox.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
