<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: football | Blog In Isolation]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/categories/football/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T20:07:32+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy C]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[why Arsenal lost the Carling Cup]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/03/01/why-arsenal-lost-carling-cup/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-01T11:42:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/03/01/why-arsenal-lost-carling-cup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I heard that Arsenal were busy making plans for their injured and
oh so inspirational captain, Cesc Fabregas, to hoist the trophy aloft
and end 6 barren years without a sniff of a trophy, I had a horrible
feeling it might end that way.</p>

<p>Can you imagine the suspended United captain, a grey suited Roy Keane,
doing that back in 1999 ? Can you even imagine Ferguson even
contemplating that option for just a second ? No. Neither can I.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[incident at Manchester City training ground]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/01/05/incident-manchester-city-training-ground/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-05T10:31:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/01/05/incident-manchester-city-training-ground</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Manchester, near England - Wednesday 5 January 2011</p>

<p>The footballing world was left reeling yesterday at shock news
emanating from Manchester City's training facility at Carrington. A
local man, Frank Booth explains: 'I always pass the City training
ground on my way to work so I always check out the players going
through their drills. Yesterday I was quite shocked to see all the
players smiling and laughing. I couldn't believe my eyes so I stopped
for a closer look.</p>

<p>'The senior players appeared to be discussing the presents they had
received at Christmas. Emmanuel Adebayor was sporting a lovely Inter
Milan shirt and Carlos Tevez was passing around some Braun hair
straighteners. All of this just two days before a crucial top of the
table clash away at Arsenal that could decide the destiny of the
league title and end 35 years of hurt. The Italian manager, Mancini,
was no better and appeared to be trying to place a Christmas Angel on
top of Yaya Toure's head using a small, portable step ladder. For a
laugh, each squad player had given Mancini an identical pale blue and
white City scarf so he was attempting to wear all 23 scarves at once.'</p>

<p>Roberto Mancini attempted to justify this unexpected outbreak of
peace, love and harmony: 'At this moment, this is very normal for the
players to be relaxed and smiling. In the recent moments, we had tough
matches over Christmas so now we relax just for one of the eight daily
training sessions. There is no problem with morale in the squad in
this moment. The Inter Milan shirt for Adebayor is not a problem. In
fact, that was, how you say, my Secret Santa gift for him'.</p>

<p><a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/fU1jvaFvI7574nHiSBTdHA?feat=embedwebsite"><img src="http://lh3.ggpht.com/_l2uGy1RGCiE/TSRCDVYRBcI/AAAAAAAABtc/o8MimwGsyww/s800/Citeh-Training.jpg" height="480" width="640" /></a></p>

<p>In an exclusive interview, Chief Executive Garry Cook attempted to
give a managerial spin on this remarkable turn of events: 'It is
absolutely ludicrous and completely untrue for amateur journalists
from tabloid newspapers to print these despicable lies just before a
crucial match. There is no suggestion whatsoever of any harmony within
the club - either on the training ground, in the dressing room or on
the coach to away matches when Joe Hart, Kolo Toure and Gareth Barry
squabble over the front seat near Roberto. Why - only this morning, I
was having a chat with Carlos about the imminent arrival of Edin Dzeko
from Wolsburg. I told Tevez, that we had been forced to offer Dzeko a
basic salary &pound;375,000 per week and Carlos was moaning that this
was higher than his &pound;350,00 a week and he was going to cry and
cry and scweam and scweam until he got an improved offer of
&pound;500,000 a day'.</p>

<p>'I replied this simply wasn't possible and anyway his annual net
income would exceed &pound;775,000 when we win the Premiership, The
Carling Cup, the Fair Play League and the Champions League this
season. Tevez didn't take this very well and exploded with rage,
mumbling something in Spanish about City not even being in the
Champions League. He then proceeded to strangle me with his snood and
Brian Marwood had to intervene and restrain him before I was choked to
death. So, rest assured, there are still internal squabbles, player
disquiet, unrest and petty arguments in the Manchester City dressing
room and I wouldn't have it any other way. It shows that the players
care. It shows the player are passionate. About money'.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[usual suspects]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/10/20/usual-suspects/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-20T09:39:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/10/20/usual-suspects</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/7TbvvBz3kX_1utlPDatYxA?feat=embedwebsite"><img src="http://lh6.ggpht.com/_l2uGy1RGCiE/TL64N1ucMiI/AAAAAAAABog/eaQQpX-FE5k/s400/Rooney.jpg"
height="177" width="400" /></a></p>

<p>United players line up for the identity parade. Paul Scholes has been
excused to 'quickly go to the toilet'.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rooney heads for the exit]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/10/14/rooney-heads-for-the-exit/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-14T12:39:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/10/14/rooney-heads-for-the-exit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I admire Wayne Rooney's skills as a footballer and I honestly don't give
a flying fig about his sordid, personal life. Unfortunately, I don't
think Wayne Rooney is blessed with that much intelligence. This isn't a
criticism, merely a statement of fact.</p>

<p>If Alex Ferguson says the sky is green, then the sky is green. If Alex
Ferguson says you have an <a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/sport1/hi/football/teams/m/man_utd/9090179.stm">ankle injury</a>, then you have an ankle
injury.</p>

<p>Sadly, for Rooney and Manchester United, I sense the writing might now
be indelibly marked on the wall for his career at Manchester United.</p>

<p>Rooney should just ask Beckham, Keane, Stam and van Nistelrooy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[non League Saturday]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/09/06/non-league-saturday/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-06T11:50:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/09/06/non-league-saturday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With no Premiership or Championship fixtures at the weekend, I went
along to watch my local non league club, Kingstonian FC, play on
Saturday afternoon.</p>

<p>[<img src="http://lh3.ggpht.com/_l2uGy1RGCiE/TITRcFe6s-I/AAAAAAAABnM/SbHHvKLtzJ4/s400/KFC.jpg" alt="image" />][]</p>

<p>Kingstonian play in the Isthmian League which is a regional league below
the Conference (sponsored by Ryman so also known as the Ryman League)
and were hosting Margate.</p>

<p>It was great to be able to saunter round to the half way line and watch
the match from behind the dugouts. It was great to hear the coaches
urging their players on and engaging in gentle banter with the match
officials - ‘Here Lino - that [offside] had to be bloody close !' It was
refreshing to be able to walk into the bar and get a drink at half-time.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, the football served up in the first half was rather
nondescript with Margate having the bulk of possession but creating
relatively few chances.</p>

<p>After the break, Kingstonian offered a little more threat, particularly
down the left side through full back Tom Bird and midfielder Dean Lodge
and Margate were thwarted by a couple of great saves from Rob Tolfrey in
the Kingston goal.</p>

<p>Against the run of play but to the delight of the assembled 400 home
spectators, Kingstonian nicked a goal and 3 points with a well taken
goal from Lodge after 84 minutes. Kingstonian are now joint top of the
Ryman League, trailing local rivals Sutton United on goal difference.</p>

<p>  [<img src="http://lh3.ggpht.com/_l2uGy1RGCiE/TITRcFe6s-I/AAAAAAAABnM/SbHHvKLtzJ4/s400/KFC.jpg" alt="image" />]: http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/cBagHm9kkAzgAgRetVL0TA?feat=embedwebsite</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
