<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: amazon | Blog In Isolation]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/categories/amazon/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T20:07:32+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy C]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[playing with the Android Kindle Reader]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/12/18/playing-android-kindle-reader/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-18T16:01:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/12/18/playing-android-kindle-reader</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Shamefully, I don't read many
<a href="http://nbrightside.com/blog/2006/11/29/testing-debut-at-book-club">books</a>
so an eBook reader has never been high on my list of priorities as it
would probably become a moderately expensive white elephant and yet
another gadget to carry around.</p>

<p>However, Amazon's high profile marketing campaign for the
<a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Kindle-Wireless-Reader-Wifi-Graphite/dp/B002Y27P46/ref=amb_link_157708327_3?pf_rd_m=A3P5ROKL5A1OLE&amp;pf_rd_s=center-1&amp;pf_rd_r=1HW1QM99QH67J6F2RA47&amp;pf_rd_t=101&amp;pf_rd_p=223297127&amp;pf_rd_i=468294)">Kindle</a> eBook reader sparked my interest sufficiently to
download the free Kindle Reader <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/feature.html/ref=red_lnd_shrt_url?ie=UTF8&amp;docId=165849822">application</a> for Android to
sample the experience of reading an eBook on a mobile device.</p>

<p>In addition, I've just purchased a higher capacity (16GB) SD card for
the Android phone which means it could replace my iPod Touch as I can
now store all my music on the Android phone and start to consolidate
two of my mobile devices. If the Android Kindle Reader application is
usable, could the <a href="http://www.htc.com/www/product/legend/overview.html">HTC Legend</a> also fulfill the role of an
eBook Reader ?</p>

<p>I downloaded Tom Reynold's '<a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Blood-Sweat-Tea-Adventures-Inner-city/dp/1905548230/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1313594801&amp;sr=8-1">Blood Sweat and Tea</a>' mainly because
it was free and I had previously <a href="http://nbrightside.com/blog/2006/08/22/in-praise-of-tom-reynolds">enjoyed</a> Reynolds' blog about
his experiences as a paramedic working for the London Ambulance
Service.</p>

<p>I have had (courtesy of my employer) an HTC Legend for 3 months and I
have been staggered at the razor sharp quality and resilence of the
screen. Even without a screen protector, the display is pristine and
crystal clear despite moderate use during that period.</p>

<p>Reading text on the Android is pretty easy on the eye. The font is large
enough and clear enough for me to read easily and the contrast is
excellent. Also, I am only reading for short periods (up to half an hour
on my commute into the city) and the fact that 'Blood Sweat and Tea' is
merely a compilation of blog posts means each story is a very short and
manageable chunk. This light, casual reading may be slightly easier on
the eyes than ploughing through 'War and Peace' for prolonged periods.</p>

<p>The larger screen on the Kindle does look great and I have heard great
things about the screen technology but there's one reason I would
currently not even contemplate buying a Kindle.</p>

<p>I selected a popular book being advertised for Christmas - 'The Fry
Chronicles' by Stephen Fry. The paper edition of this book costs
<a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Fry-Chronicles-Stephen/dp/0718154835/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1292686033&amp;sr=1-1">&pound;8.20</a> at Amazon (UK). To my amazement, the
Kindle version of the same book costs a staggering <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/The-Fry-Chronicles/dp/B0042JTA56/ref=tmm_kin_title_0?ie=UTF8&amp;m=A3TVV12T0I6NSM&amp;qid=1292686033&amp;sr=1-1">&pound;12.99</a>.</p>

<p>Yes - you read that correctly. &pound;8.20 for the hardback book and
&pound;12.99 for the electronic version of the same book for the
Kindle.</p>

<p>Now let's think about this. For the paper edition, the publisher has
to print a book on 448 pages of paper. The book also has to be bound
and this is the hardback edition. For the Kindle edition, the
publisher has to, err, well, create an electronic copy of the book.</p>

<p>How in God's name can the publisher/Amazon justify charging an
additional, extortionate, staggering premium of 58% for the Kindle
edition ?</p>

<p>Now this may be a one-off rare example and it's true that some books
are cheaper on Kindle than for the paper book. For example, the
popular 'Girl with the Dragon Tattoo' is slightly cheaper on Kindle
(&pound;2.68) versus &pound;3.89 for the paperback edition. Now I
don't have the time or inclination to exhaustively check the
comparative prices of paper versus Kindle editions for the remainder
of the best seller lists and it is true that some classic texts
(e.g. Treasure Island, Sherlock Holmes) are freely available for
eBooks.</p>

<p>However, in a sense that's irrelevant - the Kindle edition should
always, always be cheaper than the paper book - guaranteed, 100%,
every time for every book regardless. Until that is the case, I won't
be buying a Kindle or any other eBook reader.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[music for nothing]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2008/12/26/music-for-nothing/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-26T08:33:36+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2008/12/26/music-for-nothing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amazon (UK) recently
<a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/MP3-Music-Download/b/ref=amb_link_82789473_4?ie=UTF8&amp;node=77197031&amp;pf_rd_m=A3P5ROKL5A1OLE&amp;pf_rd_s=center-0&amp;pf_rd_r=0QH4MW4VEHZ0GDK985R8&amp;pf_rd_t=101&amp;pf_rd_p=464904573&amp;pf_rd_i=468294">announced</a>
an online music store and a &pound;3 discount on all music downloads on
Christmas Day and Boxing Day.</p>

<p>To download an album, you need the Amazon Download utility and the music
is MP3 format encoded at 256kbps. Best of all, the music is DRM free so
you can transfer, copy and play on any device. Normally, I like to buy
an actual CD so I can rip into whatever format I need and also as a
backup so 'The Seldom Seen Kid' by 'Elbow' was my first ever purchase of
online music</p>

<p>Downloaded music is automatically added to iTunes or Media Player and
the only glitch was that the Downloader didn't appear to work under
Google Chrome.</p>

<p>As this album (and quite a few others) only costs &pound;3, this album was
free. As in beer.</p>

<table style="width:auto;"><tr><td><a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/jtSLiWPVw_lBvdl0m2wb6Q?feat=embedwebsite"><img src="http://lh4.ggpht.com/_l2uGy1RGCiE/SVSTZXnOivI/AAAAAAAAA58/JgHgLkfe2ZA/s400/Amazon-MP3.PNG"
                                                                /></a></td></tr><tr><td style="font-family:arial,sans-serif;
                                                                font-size:11px;
                                                                text-align:right">From <a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/nbrightside/Blog?feat=embedwebsite">Blog</a></td></tr></table>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CRM]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/09/29/crm/"/>
    <updated>2005-09-29T22:08:15+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/09/29/crm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A lot of people make a lot of money out of customer relationship
management (CRM) but here is a real-life example of how customer
service affects the relationship with the customer.</p>

<p>A few weeks ago I ordered a wireless USB card and a CD (Antics by
Interpol) from Amazon. I received the normal 'Your order has been
dispatched' email within 24 hours. I waited for 10 days but nothing
turned up which was unusual because normally Amazon deliver pretty
promptly (even with the SuperSaver option).</p>

<p>I know the package hasn't been left on my doorstep in the pouring rain
by the postman and subsequently stolen as I specified the delivery
address as my place of work, specifically, to avoid this.</p>

<p>So I send Amazon a polite email informing them of the problem and
asking what can be done.</p>

<p>Amazon replied promptly, helpfully confirming when the package was
dispatched and that, unfortunately, there was no way of tracking the
item.</p>

<ul>
<li>Please note that we take full responsibility should any item become
lost or damaged while being delivered, and we are more than happy to
replace these items at a cost to ourselves. If your package does not
arrive by September 23, 2005, please contact us to confirm that it has
not been received and that your delivery address is correct for your
order, so we can investigate and take the appropriate action. *</li>
</ul>


<p>Now what was interesting about this reply was:</p>

<ul>
<li>Amazon actually read my email and answered my specific questions. It
was not a standard form letter.</li>
<li>If, after waiting two weeks and checking the delivery address was
correct, the package still did not turn up, Amazon were prepared to
send me the goods free of charge for a second time.</li>
</ul>


<p>Anyway, this story had a happy ending as the package was actually
sitting in the post room at work and they had simply forgotten to
inform me.</p>

<p>Now, after I made the initial order I discovered I could have got the
identical wireless USB card off the shelf for the same price, without
any delay in Tesco and I could have saved a whole three pounds (33%)
on the CD (at CD-WOW!).</p>

<p>However this excellent customer service gives me a increased level of
confidence of buying goods from Amazon. Could I be guaranteed the same
response if another, more expensive package from another retailer went
missing ?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[dot bombs]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/08/17/dot-bombs/"/>
    <updated>2005-08-17T15:11:12+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/08/17/dot-bombs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Returned from holiday to find correspondence lying on my doorstep from
two internet companies. Both were big names and continually in the news
during the internet boom in 1999.</p>

<p>Firstly, two cheques resulting from travelocity's takeover of
lastminute.com. Back in 2000, I applied to buy shares in lastminute.com
for me, my wife, my auntie and my dog. Thankfully, the share offering
was massively oversubscribed and I only received the minimum allocation
which reduced my subsequent losses five years later. In fact, the
lastminute takeover was very timely as I had two separate, small
shareholdings which I was stuck with as dealing costs would have
swallowed up most of the proceeds.</p>

<p>Secondly, a thick wad of legalese all the way from the United States of
America regarding a class action by shareholders (and corporate lawyers)
against Amazon. I couldn't be bothered to read all the twenty seven
pages of small print but the gist appeared to be that people bought
shares expecting to become dollar millionaires overnight and,
unsurprisingly, were bitterly disappointed when this failed to
materialise. Remember, people, the price of shares can go down as well
as up. If you want to become a dollar millionaire, don't buy shares
become a corporate lawyer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
