<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: hunour | Blog In Isolation]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/categories/hunour/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T20:07:32+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy C]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[C grade student]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/04/24/c-grade-student/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-24T13:13:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/04/24/c-grade-student</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Chatting with a good friend over dinner last night, he recounted how
his son ambushed him late one Sunday night with some economics
homework that he'd somehow manage to overlook and which simply had to
be submitted the following morning.</p>

<p>Annoyed, and after dispensing a severe bollocking, he reluctantly sat
down and gave his son some lengthy help with the complex and thorny
topic of</p>

<blockquote><p>'How does monetary policy affect the economy ?'</p></blockquote>

<p>A week later, his son mumbled 'Oh yeah - I got that Eco essay back
today and got a 'C' for it'.</p>

<p>My friend has a first class honours degree in Economics from the
University of Warwick, has spent 26 years working in finance and
banking and is currently a senior economic analyst for the leading
fund manager, Gartmore.</p>

<p>My - how we laughed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[open letter to South West trains]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/01/13/open-letter-south-west-trains/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-13T20:49:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/01/13/open-letter-south-west-trains</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Fat Controller</p>

<p>Occasionally, I use South West Trains to commute from my home in sunny
Norbiton into the City of London. However before you say anything,
don't worry, I am not a merchant banker despite what my friends say.</p>

<p>Today, in an attempt to secure a seat, I delayed my departure slightly
and caught the legendary 08:36 service from Norbiton. Unfortunately, I
narrowly missed a highly prized seat when a rather forceful gentleman,
who boarded after me, miraculously managed to reach the last vacant
seat 0.74 seconds before me. Bastard.</p>

<p>According to the official South West Trains timetable, which is
proudly pinned up in my downstairs lavatory, this service that leaves
at 08:36 should take 30 minutes, precisely, arriving at its final
destination at 09:06.</p>

<p>Today's journey left on time and arrived at Waterloo at 09:14 - a mere
8 minutes late. This isn't 5% late. This isn't 10% late. This isn't
20% late. This delay of 8 minutes on a 30 minute journey represents a
delay of 26.66667%.</p>

<p>Still, I guess I should be grateful that the cost of my weekly
TravelCard (Zones 1-5) has only increased by a paltry 6.81% from
&pound;44 to &pound;47 from January 1. If the Financial Controller
from South West Trains saw these metrics, he may well (incorrectly)
conclude that if the trains run 26% late, then the cost of the ticket
should rise by the corresponding percentage.</p>

<p>During our extended, tedious, never ending journey where we frequently
came to a grinding halt outside a station or lingered for four thought
provoking minutes adjacent to that cemetery near Clapham Junction, I
am pleased to report that we were afforded the courtesy of the
occasional helpful announcement from the guard: 'Ladies and
gentlemen. We apologise for the short delay but we are being held at a
red signal. We hope to be underway again shortly'.</p>

<p>The thing is - this delay isn't a one-off. This isn't a delay caused
by the inclement weather we experienced before Christmas. This sort of
delay is now routine.</p>

<p>In fact, these delays are so routine that people don't even moan any
more. People just shrug their shoulders, scurry along the platform
onto the tube network and accept this poor service as the norm.</p>

<p>Thankfully, I don't have an annual season ticket and I am not
condemned to using South West Trains every single working day. I am an
occasional commuter but whenever I do use the service, it invariably
arrives late. Once it was just 12 seconds late - if only the driver
hadn't lingered at Wimbledon reading the football reports in 'The
Mirror'.</p>

<p>Now, I guess it would be an interesting exercise to keep detailed
metrics for all my journeys in order to support this bold claim with
statistical evidence that could then form the basis of a compensation
claim.</p>

<p>However, I refuse to do this for two reasons; firstly I simply can't
be arsed and secondly that way lies danger and obsessive compulsive
train-spotter disorder (OCTSD). Before you know it, I would be stood,
wearing an anorak, on a wet and windy, desolate platform 11 at Clapham
Junction late at night holding a video camera, desperately trying to
capture the rare '337919' engine that powers the Gatwick Express.</p>

<p>Obviously, I don't want to waste your time and money by forcing you to
issue a stock response to a yet another stock complaint from
'Mr. Angry Commuter from Redhill' so here's my constructive suggestion
in order to significantly improve the service between Norbiton and
Waterloo.</p>

<p>Simply increase the planned duration of all journeys between Norbiton
and Waterloo to 45 minutes. Currently some journeys are scheduled to
take 28 minutes while others are supposed to take 30 minutes. This
inconsistency needs to be addressed.</p>

<p>Altering the timetable in this way will help ensure that <strong>all</strong>
journeys arrive not just on schedule but ahead of schedule as in
early.</p>

<p>This seemingly minor change will have multiple benefits; commuters
will disembark, happy and smiling, consulting their watches and
exclaiming '8 minutes early. Again. How fantastic. What a marvellous
service. I really must email South West Trains congratulating them on
this sustained improvement in the service'.</p>

<p>Following this modest increase in the estimated journey times,
customer complaints will rapidly fall to zero. This means you can sack
all the people in the customer service centre with a corresponding
beneficial effect to the very important 'bottom line'.</p>

<p>Finally, and perhaps most importantly, South West Trains will meet all
their performance targets and you will be eligible for your massive
financial bonus and a well deserved promotion to 'Morbidly Obese
Controller'.</p>

<p>Hopefully, you will consider this suggestion and implement it
initially on a pilot basis on the Shepperton line, If, as I am
convinced it will be, this change proves to be a success, this novel
and innovative change to make the railway timetable actually reflect
reality can be rolled out across the entire network in 2012. Just in
time for the Olympics.</p>

<p>Yours sincerely</p>

<p>Norman Brightside</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[to markdown or not to markdown]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/01/05/markdown-or-not-markdown/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-05T14:57:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/01/05/markdown-or-not-markdown</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.steverubel.com/">Steve Rubel</a> sings the
<a href="http://www.steverubel.com/markdown-is-a-skill-every-modern-communicator">praises</a>
of <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown</a> and good
old fashioned text editors.</p>

<p>I agree and for a long time have dithered over whether to write all of
my blog posts in Markdown. This makes sense as it simplifies the
syntax and theoretically should make writing content easier and
quicker. I was particularly struck by Caius Durling's
<a href="http://caiustheory.com/view-raw-source">use</a> of Markdown on his
Habari blog and the use of the plaintext plugin to reveal the raw
Markdown.</p>

<p>However, despite experimenting with both the Markdown
<a href="https://trac.habariproject.org/habari-extras/browser/plugins/habarimarkdown?rev=746&amp;order=name">plugin</a>
for <a href="http://habariproject.org/en/">Habari</a> and later the Markdown
filter <a href="http://drupal.org/project/markdown">module</a> for Drupal, I have
actually never taken the plunge.</p>

<p>I think the subconscious reasons behind for my reluctance to bite the
bullet and fully embrace Markdown are:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Knowing the subset of HTML tags I commonly use, I am finally
relatively comfortable composing posts in raw HTML.</p></li>
<li><p>Although Markdown uses a simple, easy to learn syntax (which is
rather the whole point after all), the Markdown markup would be a
slightly different syntax to learn and master.</p></li>
<li><p>I am (justifiably in my case) worried that I would constantly
produce incorrect Markdown syntax and hence generate flawed HTML so I
would be forever reviewing the generated HTML which again would be
time consuming and self-defeating. A side by side split, live screen
Markdown/HTML <a href="http://wmd-editor.com/examples/splitscreen">preview</a>
would be really useful.I have just discovered the
<a href="http://drupal.org/project/live">Live</a> module which looks like it
could be used in conjunction with the Markdown filter to create
similar functionality (but only when this module is ported to Drupal
7).</p></li>
<li><p>Sometimes I embed images from Picasweb or YouTube and I'm not sure
how these HTML embeds would work in Markdown or whether the Markdown
processor will accept raw HTML for these occasional exceptions.</p></li>
<li><p>Drupal supports different filter types on a per post basis but I
have concerns about attempting to migrate a blog containing a mixture
of HTML and Markdown posts to different blog platforms and I'm hardly
likely to convert 1,000 historic posts to Markdown. However, if the
Markdown is processed and the generated HTML is stored in the
database, this may not be a problem. Another obvious solution is
trying to curb this constant urge to tinker with the underlying
technology powering this blog but that is unlikely to happen.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>Anyway, time to stop procrastinating. I have managed to write this
post in Markdown and already I like the modified, simpler syntax, so I
will endeavour to follow Steve Rubel's advice and join the ranks of
the 'modern communicators'.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[incident at Manchester City training ground]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/01/05/incident-manchester-city-training-ground/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-05T10:31:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/01/05/incident-manchester-city-training-ground</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Manchester, near England - Wednesday 5 January 2011</p>

<p>The footballing world was left reeling yesterday at shock news
emanating from Manchester City's training facility at Carrington. A
local man, Frank Booth explains: 'I always pass the City training
ground on my way to work so I always check out the players going
through their drills. Yesterday I was quite shocked to see all the
players smiling and laughing. I couldn't believe my eyes so I stopped
for a closer look.</p>

<p>'The senior players appeared to be discussing the presents they had
received at Christmas. Emmanuel Adebayor was sporting a lovely Inter
Milan shirt and Carlos Tevez was passing around some Braun hair
straighteners. All of this just two days before a crucial top of the
table clash away at Arsenal that could decide the destiny of the
league title and end 35 years of hurt. The Italian manager, Mancini,
was no better and appeared to be trying to place a Christmas Angel on
top of Yaya Toure's head using a small, portable step ladder. For a
laugh, each squad player had given Mancini an identical pale blue and
white City scarf so he was attempting to wear all 23 scarves at once.'</p>

<p>Roberto Mancini attempted to justify this unexpected outbreak of
peace, love and harmony: 'At this moment, this is very normal for the
players to be relaxed and smiling. In the recent moments, we had tough
matches over Christmas so now we relax just for one of the eight daily
training sessions. There is no problem with morale in the squad in
this moment. The Inter Milan shirt for Adebayor is not a problem. In
fact, that was, how you say, my Secret Santa gift for him'.</p>

<p><a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/fU1jvaFvI7574nHiSBTdHA?feat=embedwebsite"><img src="http://lh3.ggpht.com/_l2uGy1RGCiE/TSRCDVYRBcI/AAAAAAAABtc/o8MimwGsyww/s800/Citeh-Training.jpg" height="480" width="640" /></a></p>

<p>In an exclusive interview, Chief Executive Garry Cook attempted to
give a managerial spin on this remarkable turn of events: 'It is
absolutely ludicrous and completely untrue for amateur journalists
from tabloid newspapers to print these despicable lies just before a
crucial match. There is no suggestion whatsoever of any harmony within
the club - either on the training ground, in the dressing room or on
the coach to away matches when Joe Hart, Kolo Toure and Gareth Barry
squabble over the front seat near Roberto. Why - only this morning, I
was having a chat with Carlos about the imminent arrival of Edin Dzeko
from Wolsburg. I told Tevez, that we had been forced to offer Dzeko a
basic salary &pound;375,000 per week and Carlos was moaning that this
was higher than his &pound;350,00 a week and he was going to cry and
cry and scweam and scweam until he got an improved offer of
&pound;500,000 a day'.</p>

<p>'I replied this simply wasn't possible and anyway his annual net
income would exceed &pound;775,000 when we win the Premiership, The
Carling Cup, the Fair Play League and the Champions League this
season. Tevez didn't take this very well and exploded with rage,
mumbling something in Spanish about City not even being in the
Champions League. He then proceeded to strangle me with his snood and
Brian Marwood had to intervene and restrain him before I was choked to
death. So, rest assured, there are still internal squabbles, player
disquiet, unrest and petty arguments in the Manchester City dressing
room and I wouldn't have it any other way. It shows that the players
care. It shows the player are passionate. About money'.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
