<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Blog In Isolation]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T20:07:32+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy C]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[the awkward second post]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/the-awkward-second-post/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-14T19:07:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/the-awkward-second-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Octopress is great</p>

<ul>
<li>Uses Google to provide site search</li>
<li>Archives builtin</li>
<li>Tag support</li>
<li>Draft posts</li>
<li>Local preview</li>
<li>Markdown markup</li>
<li>Google+, Disqus, Google Analytics support</li>
<li>Incremental deployment</li>
<li>Deployment to Amazon S3</li>
<li>Fast as lightning</li>
</ul>


<p>Wish I&#8217;d bitten the bullet earlier.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-14T16:49:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my first post in Octopress.</p>

<p>The text uses <em>Markdown</em> which is <strong>marvellous</strong>.</p>

<p>My favourite blogging platforms are:</p>

<ul>
<li>Octopress</li>
<li>Habari</li>
<li>Drupal</li>
<li>WordPress</li>
</ul>


<p>The <a href="http://bbc.co.uk">BBC</a> is a popular Web site.</p>

<p>End of message.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[migration plan]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/migration-plan/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-14T15:55:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/migration-plan</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Loose thoughts on the plan of attack for the blog migration:</p>

<ol>
<li>Install Octopress locally</li>
<li>Configure S3 and install a dummy Web site.</li>
<li>Use&#8217;s3cmd&#8217; to upload test site to Amazon S3</li>
<li>Test incremental uploads. This is a firm requirement.</li>
<li>Full database backup of existing Drupal blog</li>
<li>Take backup of Drupal installation (additional modules, scripts).</li>
<li>Install vanilla Drupal 7 locally.</li>
<li>Install copy of the existing Dupal blog in local version (overwrite database ?).</li>
<li>Use the Drupal to Octopress migration script. This extracts nodes from the database and creates Markdown files for each post, This script is probably for Drupal 6 so some tweaks (major rewrite) may be needed for bleeding edge Drupal 7. URL aliasing is supposedly supported.</li>
<li>Test the various elements in the <a href="http://nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/blog-migration-checklist">checklist</a>. Disqus comments need the correct domain name so will have to come last.</li>
<li>Configure a redirect from &#8216;nbrightside.com&#8217; to the Amazon URL. I can see trouble and lots of Googl&#8217;ing here.</li>
<li>Place source code (Markdown posts) into GitHub repository.</li>
<li>Put kettle on.</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[blog migration checklist]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/blog-migration/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-14T15:45:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/blog-migration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am a veteran of blog migrations with the scars to prove it. Here is a handy &#8216;cut out and keep&#8217; checklist of the important things I normally forget:</p>

<ul>
<li>Permalink structure. Try to preserve the existing permalink structure to save hours of pain. This is particularly important when using Disqus (although there is a URL migration utility for Disqus).</li>
<li>Typically, I like to have &#8216;Archives&#8217;, &#8216;About&#8217; and a &#8216;Contact&#8217; page.</li>
<li>Tag support including a &#8216;Tags&#8217; page.</li>
<li>Images. I have learned to upload all photos and screenshots to PicasaWeb and intentionally de-couple images from the blog platform.</li>
<li>Sitemap support. Helps search engines index the site.</li>
<li>RSS/Atom support . Previously I have always used Feedburner (although I may follow Google&#8217;s example and sever this dependency) and simply use the native feed. Less is more.</li>
<li>Comments. Static site generators are slightly limited here (compared with proper blogging platforms) so I guess I will continue to use Disqus. Mind you, for the number of comments versus spam, I may also dispense with comments and invite people to use Google+ or identi.ca.</li>
<li>Themes. It would be desirable to be able to change themes to avoid having the same look and feel and every other Octopress blog.</li>
</ul>


<p>Please feel free to add your own tips in the comments.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Autumn migration]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/autumn-migration/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-14T14:45:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/09/14/autumn-migration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My Web hosting package (provided by Bluehost) expires in October. As
this blog is essentially dead (the last post was a one-liner 8 months
ago), the sensible and logical thing to do would be to kill the blog
and save £5 a month.</p>

<p>Originally I
<a href="http://nbrightside.com/blog/2006/10/24/new-dawn-fades">purchased</a> the
domain name &#8216;nbrightside.com&#8217; and the Web hosting for a couple of
reasons:</p>

<ul>
<li>I wanted to use self hosted WordPress without some of the restrictions imposed by WordPress.com</li>
<li>I wanted to play with some of the packaged applications offered by Bluehost.</li>
<li>I wanted access to a Linux environment, mainly to build, install, experiment with various open source software tools and packages which needed a LAMP stack.</li>
</ul>


<p>It&#8217;s really questionable whether I need to maintain this Web presence
but, on balance, I&#8217;d like to keep the site alive for a little longer.</p>

<p>WordPress, Drupal, Habari et al are all fantastic blogging platforms
but rather overkill for this simple, single user blog. For a while, I
have been fascinated and trying to resist the temptation of the
simplicity and power of static Web site generators like
<a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a> and
<a href="http://hyde.github.com/">Hyde</a>.</p>

<p>Last year, I even ported the complete contents of this Drupal 7 blog
to a locally installed version of Hyde and labouriously fixed up lots
of hyperlinks just so the Markdown looked neater.</p>

<p>The completely logical and sensible decision would be to simply
resurrect this Hyde environment, re-sync the last couple of one liner
blog posts, configure a automatic redirect and use rsync to upload
this site to some alternative, cheaper (or free) Web hosting.</p>

<p>So, I have decided to use <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> and
<a href="http://aws.typepad.com/aws/2011/02/host-your-static-website-on-amazon-s3.html">Amazon
S3</a>
to host this humble, annually updated blog in the future. I may be
able to reuse some of the Hyde content with judicious use of sed to
convert the meta data in the header sections or I may just start
afresh.</p>

<p>No - I am no mad.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[blog maintenance]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/02/02/blog-maintenance/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-02T09:39:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/02/02/blog-maintenance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Time to upgrade Drupal again. Yesterday version
<a href="http://drupal.org/drupal-7.12">7.12</a> was released and this blog is
currently running a very outdated (and probably insecure)
7.4. Although Drupal 7 included automatic update for modules and
themes, updating the core Drupal software still needs manual
intervention and takes time.</p>

<p>Over the years, the main self-hosted blog platforms I have used are:</p>

<ul>
<li>WordPress - one-click updates. Quick and easy. By far the best and most robust solution. Never let me down.</li>
<li>Habari - Official Habari releases were fairly infrequent so I chose to I track the latest development version so upgrade was manual but as simple as typing &#8216;$ svn update&#8217;. Rolling back was needed on a couple of occasions but possible simply by reverting to the previous SVN version ($ svn update -r <nnn>).</li>
<li>Drupal - manual <a href="http://drupal.org/node/1285892">update</a>. Involves taking the site offline, copying files, thinking, run &#8216;update.php&#8217;, copying files back again, bringing the site back online and a little time. Slightly tedious as Drupal tend to to release a new version of the core software every month or so with a nagging email reminder to do the right thing.</li>
</ul>


<p>I have also noticed that my sitemap hasn&#8217;t been generated in 6 months
and doesn&#8217;t include the most recent entries. In addition, some (old)
posts have been marked as &#8216;Never Update&#8217; but after some housekeeping
to modify some permalinks to fix various &#8216;404 - Not found&#8217; errors,
these old entries now need to be regenerated.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[right said Fred]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/02/01/right-said-fred/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-01T09:50:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/02/01/right-said-fred</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I think it is entirely right and proper that Sir Fred Goodwin has been stripped of his knighthood.</p>

<p>After all, I am a shareholder in the Royal Bank of Scotland and his incompetence has cost me a significant amount of money and pushed back my retirement age to 87.</p>

<p>In fact, why stop there ? Personally, I find it objectionable that Freddie&#8217;s surname includes the word &#8216;Good&#8217;. This man is not good - in fact, he is a very bad man so I suggest he should henceforth be known as &#8216;Fred Win&#8217;.</p>

<p>Oh no. Wait hang on - the word &#8216;win&#8217; also has positive connotations associated with victory and happiness (see also Charlie Sheen and &#8216;Winning&#8217;). This will never do so I insist the word &#8216;Win&#8217; is also stripped from his legal name.</p>

<p>So now, the former head of RBS should simply be known as &#8216;Fred&#8217;.</p>

<p>Investigations continue into whether Fred has a middle name.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Year resolution]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/01/01/new-year-resolution/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-01T19:53:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2012/01/01/new-year-resolution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Must. Blog. More.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Am Not Left Handed - This Is Now]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/ianl-this-is-now/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-12T12:20:27+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/ianl-this-is-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is part 2 of an interview with Kathryn and Daniel from &#8216;I Am Not
Left Handed&#8217;. The first part &#8216;That Was Then&#8217; is available
<a href="http://nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/ianl-that-was-then">here</a>.</p>

<p><em>This might seem like (another) weird question but then again I am
slightly weird myself. I realise you&#8217;re a relatively young band but
are they any songs of your own that you don&#8217;t like and would not
contemplate playing live ? Maybe early songs that you have now
outgrown. Or are you fiercely proud of everything you&#8217;ve ever produced
?</em></p>

<p><em>I mean everyone has songs by their favourite bands that they can&#8217;t
 stand.  For example, I love R.E.M but simply can not stand &#8216;Losing My
 Religion&#8217;.</em></p>

<p><em>I&#8217;m not articulating this very well - I guess I&#8217;m thinking of when
Kurt used to get completely fed up with endless requests for &#8216;Smells
Like Teen Spirit&#8217;.</em></p>

<p>D: I don&#8217;t know that we feel relatively young!  Making decent music
takes time, we&#8217;ve years of unfocused songs and struggling bands behind
us.  I think as we get better at it, and letting the songs flow more
naturally, we&#8217;re happier with the end result.  Kathryn definitely has
very high standards, she won&#8217;t let us even record something that she&#8217;s
not 100% behind, whereas I tend to be a bit more of the attitude, oh
we can just tinker with it a bit.  There are one or two songs that
I&#8217;ve forced a bit more, and as a result they just haven&#8217;t had the same
staying power - &#8216;Falling&#8217; from Yes Means No is one of those, we don&#8217;t
ever play it live anymore.</p>

<p>K: Though who knows, maybe it&#8217;s just waiting for us to come and
rewrite it&#8230; we do end up doing that a lot.</p>

<p><em>Mind you, I call you a young band but I saw an interview with you in
 July 2009 when you talk of gigs, videos and songs, so when exactly
 did you actually form ?</em></p>

<p>D: As I say, Kathryn and I have been doing this for a few years, in
different iterations but I think the end of 2007 was when we really
worked out where we were going and added Benji - we had another
guitarist who left, and it really made us have to sit down and rewrite
all of our songs as a three-piece, which was the best thing that ever
happened to us.</p>

<p><em>OK - which of the following appear on your iPod/turntable/cassette player ?</em>
<em></p>

<ul>
    <li>Idlewild</li>
    <li>Nirvana</li>
    <li>R.E.M.</li>
    <li>The Duke Spirit</li>
    <li>The Fall</li>
    <li>The National</li>
    <li>The Smiths</li>
    <li>The Chameleons (who ?)</li>
</ul>


<p></em></p>

<p>D: A little Idlewild, a fair amount of Nirvana.  I&#8217;ve done sound for
the Duke Spirit but don&#8217;t have any of their recordings.  The Fall not
at all, The National I keep hearing about, but I haven&#8217;t managed to
get into them despite a couple of casual listenings. The
Smiths&#8230; let&#8217;s just say I&#8217;m a big fan of Johnny Marr, less so of the
rest of the band.  No idea about the Chameleons, sorry.</p>

<p>K: I have plenty Idlewild, Nirvana, R.E.M, Duke Spirit and even The
Chameleons. None of the Fall, the National and definitely not the
Smiths. Marr is great but I find Morrissey just too pretentious. Take
that comment about the killings in Norway being nothing compared to
the number of animals killed for KFC and McDonalds every day. Every
time he puts out a quote I just think - I have absolutely nothing in
common with your way of thinking.</p>

<p><em>You&#8217;ve covered &#8216;Lousy Reputation&#8217; by &#8216;We Are Scientists&#8217; and &#8216;I Will
 Follow You Into The Dark&#8217; by &#8216;Death Cab For Cutie&#8217;. What other songs
 have you covered ? Or soundcheck to ?</em></p>

<p>K: We always had a policy from the beginning of only playing our own
material, and not covering other people&#8217;s songs.  I think we&#8217;d heard
too many other bands in Dublin who&#8217;d include a cover in their set, and
at the end, that&#8217;s all that people would remember.</p>

<p>D: But as we&#8217;ve become more confident in our sound, we&#8217;re loosening
that up a little.  In a different band, we did used to play a mixed-up
version of &#8216;Where Is My Mind?&#8217;, with Kathryn on drums.  We&#8217;re toying
with a cover of a <a href="http://www.therapyquestionmark.co.uk/">Therapy?</a> song at the moment, the
harmonies are really nice, we&#8217;re just trying to get it to work
instrumentally.</p>

<p><em>Are you all those sickening self-taught people who can play a song
back perfectly seconds after listening to it ? Or did you have any
formal music tuition ?</em></p>

<p>D: I&#8217;m very much from a classical music background, I played the viola
for years, but never really found it that satisfying - I do think the
classical education system with its focus more on reading music rather
than listening is a much poorer way to learn. Since I started playing
guitar and bass in my teens, I&#8217;ve found it a lot more enjoyable, just
playing by feel and with what sounds good, and essentially trying to
forget how to read music.  I do get jealous of Kathryn sometimes,
she&#8217;s a far better ear for harmonies and sense of rhythm than me. Then
again, she keeps me on my toes and makes me up my game, so it&#8217;s not
all bad!</p>

<p><em>When recording the new album, it appeared you hired a big house in
the country with a studio so you were able to live together while
recording ?</em></p>

<p><em>Did this help and accelerate the creative process or did it ever get
 claustrophobic ?</em></p>

<p>K: It&#8217;s a medium-sized house in the very beautiful surroundings of
Northamptonshire.  We&#8217;ve been in and out of London reasonably
regularly too, so it hasn&#8217;t been complete isolation, which I think is
good in the sanity stakes.  It&#8217;s a great place though, there&#8217;s horses
out one window, a river at the bottom of the garden and a graveyard
next door to keep an eye on us. Sometimes the local kids go there to
make out. That&#8217;s about as uncomfortable as it gets though.</p>

<p>D: We&#8217;ve put the studio together ourselves.  It&#8217;s been so great to
actually have the space to make and record the music properly, with a
proper live room and control room, it&#8217;s really been a fertile time for
us in terms of writing new songs - the hard bit is finishing them,
we&#8217;ve a lot of new things we like, but trying to coax them into a
recordable shape is trickier.</p>

<p><em>Now we turn to face the future. You finished recording the new album
 &#8216;The Fire And The Sigh&#8217; a few weeks ago. Is a release date imminent
 ?</em></p>

<p>D: Not quite finished yet!  I think we were initially trying to
release some singles ahead of the album, so we worked hard on Alone
and put it out. But as we&#8217;ve progressed, we just want to make sure the
album is complete and everything&#8217;s as perfect as it can be before we
put anything else out.  So you won&#8217;t hear any more until it&#8217;s all
perfect.</p>

<p>K: The end of August is D-Day, but then there&#8217;s mastering and artwork
and more videos to worry about, so it&#8217;ll be another couple of
months. All the advice we&#8217;ve had is that indie bands tend to rush
their releases, and it all comes out in a muddle.  This is a big
statement for us, so we want to make sure everything&#8217;s right before it
goes out in the world.</p>

<p><em>Oh I nearly forgot - what is the origin of the name - &#8216;The Fire And
 The Sigh&#8217; ?</em></p>

<p>D: I like album titles that are lines from a song on the album, almost
as much as I hate album titles that are the same as one of the song
titles, I think that&#8217;s just lazy.  I don&#8217;t know about the others, but
layout: post
comments: true
for me, The Fire &amp; The Sigh really sums up the tone of Kathryn&#8217;s
writing, I think she writes about things that make her angry or
melancholy. I can see Kathryn laughing as I&#8217;m saying this, but that&#8217;s
how it seems to me!</p>

<p>K: I&#8217;m only laughing a little bit&#8230;</p>

<p><em>I just love &#8216;The Place That Won&#8217;t Take Me Back&#8217;. I&#8217;m almost reluctant
 to ask this as I firmly believe you don&#8217;t really want or need to know
 what the lyrics are about. It&#8217;s much better left to your
 imagination.</em></p>

<p><em>I remember when I discovered that &#8216;The Geese of Beverley Road&#8217; by The
 National was actually about ruffians setting off car alarms. I was
 distraught for 5 days.</em></p>

<p><em>So, although it&#8217;s fraught with danger, could you describe what the
 &#8216;The Place&#8230;&#8217; is about ?</em></p>

<p>K: I&#8217;ve kept a couple of blogs over the years. I&#8217;m sort of dodging
this question for fear of ruining the song for you now, but there are
two posts I can think of, that were about how I write songs. They
might help make up for not answering.</p>

<p>One here:
<a href="http://wealthvsfame.wordpress.com/2010/01/17/its-only-time">http://wealthvsfame.wordpress.com/2010/01/17/its-only-time</a></p>

<p>And one about how it&#8217;s probably more obvious an answer than it would
have been in an older song here:
<a href="http://www.iamnotlefthanded.com/listen.html">http://www.iamnotlefthanded.com/listen.html</a></p>

<p><em>Glastonbury has just been and gone. So has Bono. Do you like
 festivals ? Any plans to appear in any this summer ?</em></p>

<p>D: Festivals are okay, I did go to 29 one summer when I was working
with the Rumble Strips, which I think burned me out on them a
little. Playing at festivals, it can be hard to get a real rapport
with the crowd, we like things a bit more intimate where you can have
a back and forth with people.  Because of the recording, we&#8217;ve not
been applying for festivals this summer, we may find one or two next
year that we like.</p>

<p><em>Can you believe Larry Mullen Jnr is 49 years old ? He looks about
 19.</em></p>

<p>D: He&#8217;s always been consistently youthful, he looks like he could join
up with Westlife any minute&#8230; I think the rest of U2 may have been
keeping him in a freezer between shows.  By the way, I&#8217;m not an ardent
supporter of U2, but if you haven&#8217;t recently, go back and watch the
video to Elevation.  The Edge is hilarious.</p>

<p>K: It&#8217;s funny you should mention this. I wasn&#8217;t so big a fan of U2
until I saw them live at Slane Castle back in 2001. Over the whole
day, I&#8217;d sneaked from the very back of the crowd to the very front (it
pays to be tiny at most gigs - unless it&#8217;s an Audioslave show, though
that&#8217;s a whole other story) And just as the drums kicked in I was hit
by this wall of sound.  And it was like nothing I&#8217;d ever heard
before. &#8216;Where The Streets Have No Name&#8217; still stands as the best song
I&#8217;ve ever heard live.</p>

<p>Conversely, my home town is the only place that U2 have officially
said they&#8217;ll never play again. When they had one of their first gigs
there back in the late 70s, the crowd threw pennies at them til they
got off stage. Whoops. No accounting for taste I suppose.</p>

<p><em>&#8216;Lifelines&#8217; seems a pretty dark love song - &#8216;No more talks of who let
 who down&#8217;.</em></p>

<p>K: A dark lovesong to friendship after a break-up, is probably closer
to the truth. I wrote a blogpost recently that sort of relates, if you
think anyone&#8217;s curious. The post isn&#8217;t about Lifelines, but it&#8217;s on a
similar theme</p>

<p><a href="http://everythingbuttheocean.tumblr.com/post/8608907557/happy-endings">http://everythingbuttheocean.tumblr.com/post/8608907557/happy-endings</a></p>

<p><em>I love the new single &#8216;Alone&#8217;. This song first appeared as a 75
 second tune on the &#8216;Time To Leave&#8217; EP and was embellished to evolve
 into a fully fledged 4 mins 30 second perfect pop song complete with
 a homemade zombie video.</em></p>

<p><em>Did you always intend to develop the song in this way ? Was the EP
 version just a taster ?</em></p>

<p>D: It&#8217;s kind of representative of the way we write - things tend to
hang around as shortened versions for quite a while, until something
else occurs to us and it takes a new direction.  I think Kathryn had
written it about 2 days before we recorded it for &#8216;Time To Leave&#8217;. The
same happened with &#8216;Boats&#8217; on &#8216;Yes Means No&#8217;&#8230;</p>

<p>Wonderful IANL quote from <a href="http://www.thebandwagontv.com/?p=302">bandwagon</a></p>

<blockquote><p>&#8216;We don&#8217;t play pop music, we don&#8217;t write music for art&#8217;s sake, we
don&#8217;t represent any movements, we&#8217;re not hip, we&#8217;re not cutting
edge, we don&#8217;t dress to be cool. We do manage ourselves, we write
our own songs, we do our own recordings, we shoot our own videos, we
design our own covers, we made our own website. We&#8217;re not generally
negative people, oh yes, and we&#8217;re not lefthanded.&#8217;</p></blockquote>

<p><em>OK - final question.</em></p>

<p><em>What plans, hopes, ambitions does the band have for the rest of 2011
 and into 2012 ?</em></p>

<p>D: The big plan is to get the album out.  We&#8217;re so excited to finally
be making a full-length statement.  A lot of people are saying that
the 40 minute album is dead as a concept, that singles are the way of
the future, but I think there&#8217;s very much something to be said for
sitting down and listening to an album through for 40 minutes.  It&#8217;s
the length of the human attention span, at least that&#8217;s what they told
us in school as we had 40 minute lessons.</p>

<p>K: At the moment, we are focused on finishing the recording, so we&#8217;re
trying not to put too many plans in place until everything&#8217;s
ready. Another US tour is definitely on the cards, and hopefully some
Canadian dates too.  We&#8217;ll be back to Ireland as well, for the Irish
release and in the medium term, we really want to get to some of
continental Europe: Spain, Germany and the Netherlands in
particular. I think we&#8217;ll just have to see where the wind blows us -
we ended up touring the last EP for two years, so we&#8217;ll just have to
see how the album does, and where people want us to come and play.</p>

<p>D: We are hoping to start doing a regular internet show tho, maybe
once a month - in some ways we feel like our home town is online these
days, more so than Dublin or London, so if we can connect with people
there, so much the better! We&#8217;ve some video ideas we&#8217;re excited about
making too, we&#8217;re just trying to keep on the straight and narrow for
this last stretch.  We are letting ourselves out for one London show
in September - it&#8217;s for a fantastic children&#8217;s charity.  It&#8217;s in Bush
Hall, on the 23rd of September.  Details as always are on the website
at: <a href="http://www.iamnotlefthanded.com">www.iamnotlefthanded.com</a></p>

<p><em>Many thanks for your time and all the best.</em></p>

<p>D: Thanks for all the thoughtful, wide-ranging questions.  I always
enjoy having the time to answer interviews like this, it makes me get
my head in order - the act of writing things down means you have to
commit to positions on things you may not have forced yourself to
decide about until now.</p>

<p>K: Just so :) It&#8217;s been a pleasure.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Am Not Left Handed - That Was Then]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/ianl-that-was-then/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-12T12:18:42+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/ianl-that-was-then</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>OK - let&#8217;s get the boring stuff out of the way.</em></p>

<p><em>How did you all meet and form the band ? Please don&#8217;t tell me you
posted an ad in &#8216;Melody Maker&#8217;.</em></p>

<p>D: Kathryn and I met in Dublin, we were working on a summer course
together.  We both played in different bands at the time, I was
fronting my own band, Coyote Blue, and Kathryn was playing keys and
singing backing vocals with some friends of hers.  We&#8217;d been staying
up late at night with the other counsellors, a few of whom were
musicians too, and there were guitars floating around, but Kathryn
kept refusing any chance to accept the guitar and play a song.</p>

<p>I knew that she was musical through some conversations we&#8217;d had
before, so eventually I persuaded her to sneak away to a different
room.  After playing several songs at her, and relentless asking, she
eventually surrendered and played me a song.  I was blown away, and
just knew right then that she should be playing her own music.</p>

<p>We played with a couple of different line-ups in Dublin together,
before parting for a while.  Kathryn went to California and I moved to
London. I was working in the Camden Barfly with Benji.  We used to do
every Friday night, I was doing sound, he was stage managing.  With
six bands a night, doing 13-hour shifts, it was pretty much life in
the trenches - after a couple of years when Kathryn came over to
London, Benji was the only choice for a drummer, we&#8217;ve never regretted
it for a moment.</p>

<p><em>The Irish are well known for their love of music. Did music play a
big part in your childhood ?  Were you dragged into the pub every
Saturday night to play the bodhrán by your Father&#8217;s side ?</em></p>

<p>K: Not so much with the bodhrán on Saturday nights, but one of my
earliest memories was after Mass on Sunday mornings, we used to go to
a pub on the river, just down the road from the church. This great
band played there every weekend, everything from soul to country. They
had a full brass section and this amazing guitarist with the fastest
fingers.</p>

<p>Later on, we got a piano in the house and dad used to sit beside me,
playing songs I still don&#8217;t know the names of, and saying the chords
so I could play along. So I seem to have inherited my dad&#8217;s knack for
playing by ear, but am completely rubbish at reading sheet music.</p>

<p>D: I think Kathryn had a more authentic Irish childhood.  I was raised
in Belfast, before moving to Dublin, and even then my family were of a
Church of Ireland background rather than the traditional Irish
Catholic.  So I was actually raised with classical music, playing the
viola in youth orchestras and such.  My father might not know a
Bodhrán if he saw one&#8230;</p>

<p><em>You announced that you all &#8216;quit your jobs&#8217; in August 2010 to focus
 solely on the band. What did you both do before you were rock stars
 ?</em></p>

<p>K: We did quit our jobs last August to go on tour in the US. I worked
in film production, which means I spend most of my work day secretly
coming up with ideas for our next video, and stealing ideas as to how
we can make them on a low budget.</p>

<p>D: I worked as a touring sound engineer, with bands like the Young
Knives, The Rumble Strips and Blood Red Shoes.  It&#8217;s not an easy
business making money just from music these days, so we still do a bit
of work on the side to make sure we still have a roof over our heads
while we&#8217;re finishing the album.</p>

<p>K: I think the balance used to be about two thirds of our time
working, one third being in a band and now it&#8217;s reversed.  Hopefully
as the band grows, we&#8217;ll be able to drop that last third completely.</p>

<p><em>And what did your Mummies say when they heard your decision ?</em></p>

<p>K: Mum was supportive. Lots of comments about how I&#8217;d been working too
hard, and wouldn&#8217;t this be a good time to write a book while we were
on the road. I suspect if they ever made a movie of the band&#8217;s
adventures, it would be more of a feel-good comedy and less of a
gritty drama.</p>

<p>D: I&#8217;m the middle of three boys, and have a very awesome older brother
who works for the International Red Cross, really fulfilling most
everything my parents could want from a son.  I think they resigned
themselves a long while ago to the fact that I&#8217;m going to do what I&#8217;m
going to do.  They&#8217;re just happy I&#8217;m not in jail or on the streets&#8230;</p>

<p><em>I&#8217;ve never been in a band, I can&#8217;t play a note and I can&#8217;t
sing. However, none of this stops me from being acutely interested in
the song writing process.</em></p>

<p><em>A couple of my favourite bands, R.E.M. and Nirvana, appear to write
 the music and then overlay random snippets of scribbled lyrics from
 notebooks.</em></p>

<p><em>I get the impression you don&#8217;t operate this way and you write short
 stories - poems almost - that are then set to music.</em></p>

<p><em>Could you describe how the band produces music ?</em></p>

<p>D: In the early days, it used to be more the case that one or the
other of us would write a song alone, mainly Kathryn, and then it
would be brought to the band for development of the music.  Nowadays
most of our songwriting comes out of the two of us playing together.</p>

<p>K: We&#8217;ll just get a spark of something - the guitar and bass at the
start of &#8216;Boats&#8217; is a good example, we were just playing those chords
and they sounded&#8230; right, I guess is the best description.</p>

<p>D: Then when we have something we like, Kathryn&#8217;ll work out a vocal
melody, and then we bring it to Benji.  He&#8217;s our representation of the
world - if it works for him, if he can play something awesome with it,
it&#8217;s a good song.  If not, it&#8217;s back to the drawing board.  Finalised
lyrics tend to come at the very end.</p>

<p>K: We&#8217;re not one of those bands who write songs in twelve minutes. It
can take anything up to a year of having a few bars of something
before it&#8217;s ready to be turned into a full song.</p>

<p><em>Why are the <a href="http://iamnotlefthanded.tumblr.com/post/863604483/thing-a-week-21-alone-live">videos</a> from the early Camden sessions &#8216;Private&#8217;
 ?</em></p>

<p>D: I think, earlier this year we wanted to clean-up our YouTube stream
- we wanted to just present the best material we have.</p>

<p>K: We can get a bit nitpicky over our own performances. They were
recordings we did quite fast for our Thing A Week last year, they were
fun to do at the time, but we didn&#8217;t always think we were doing
ourselves justice in the long-term.</p>

<p><em>Robbie Williams never managed to &#8216;break&#8217; American despite being
 successful in Europe and having the multi-million pound backing of
 EMI. Yet you have already toured America !</em></p>

<p><em>Why is that ? Is it because Daniel&#8217;s view of the band&#8217;s music as
 &#8216;American Indie&#8217; means your music is well received there ? Or did you
 just fancy a trip to DisneyLand ?</em></p>

<p>D: A large part of it is that I think we don&#8217;t resonate so well in the
UK. We do have several lovely supporters here, but we don&#8217;t fit into
the standard UK indie scene, so it&#8217;s been a struggle trying to find
our own way.  We just kept getting a lot of requests from people to
come playing in the US, and we always like to go where we&#8217;re invited.</p>

<p>K: At the moment, we&#8217;re thinking about moving to San Francisco for a
while to see how being based in the US would work for us.  It&#8217;s so
great that With the internet these days, location becomes less
relevant - we can still keep up with everyone online and spread our
music, no matter where we are in the world.</p>

<p><em>I was very interested to read that you manged to <a href="http://iamnotlefthanded.tumblr.com/post/1181380920/financed-where-we-go-from-here">raise</a>
 $11,000 funding using crowd sourcing on slicethepie.com as opposed to
 a lucrative record deal. How did that come about ?</em></p>

<p>K: The great thing with SliceThePie, is that it&#8217;s one site where you
could put up the music and get it listened to and reviewed completely
anonymously by strangers.  The people they select for their showcase
are the people who get ranked the highest in this blind reviewing.  So
when we were put into the showcase last January, we knew that we&#8217;d
earned our place, purely because of the music.  It was a great
affirmation for ourselves, as much as anything.  Of course when we
were in the showcase we had to work our asses off and hustle and try
and encourage people to invest - which they did!  We hit our total in
September and since then we&#8217;ve been writing, rehearsing, setting up
the studio and recording.  We&#8217;re coming into the final stretch now,
just want to make sure everything&#8217;s as strong as it can be.  It&#8217;s been
a slow process this year, we&#8217;ve been learning a lot about how to
record an album as much as writing one.</p>

<p>D: The SliceThePie thing came about in a really nice way actually. The
whole industry&#8217;s pretty confused at the moment, record labels really
are not investing in young bands at all - you need to prove you&#8217;re
having decent success on your own before they&#8217;ll touch you.  At the
same time, there are a million different websites, promising you
everything from songwriting competitions, to festival slots, to gear
and cash prizes.  The problem with most of these, and one thing we
hate with a passion, is that they all involve getting bands to tell
their friends to sign-up and vote for them.  They&#8217;re basically just
using bands to advertise their websites or products.  Music for us is
not a popularity contest, it&#8217;s all about the one-on-one connection
that you make with a song.  Just because you might like our music, the
last thing we want you to do is sign up for something and get
subjected to spam and advertising.  The only thing we ask from our
fans is that if they like the music, then share it with their friends.</p>

<p><em>You use Tumblr for your blog. You use Feedburner. You use Google
 Analytics. You use Twitter. You have created your own Web site. Come
 on, own up - who&#8217;s the geeky one in the band ?</em></p>

<p>K: We&#8230; probably both slightly geeky, though we&#8217;ve never thought of
ourselves that way.  It just makes sense to use the best tools
available, and we have been doing this a while, so we&#8217;ve tried a lot
of things over the years.</p>

<p><em>And does this individual torture themselves monitoring downloads,
 page views, sales and tweets on an hourly basis ?</em></p>

<p>D: Sales are always nice to know about&#8230;  The rest is useful,
particularly when you have information about where in the world people
are coming from etc.  It&#8217;s not worth obsessing over, but it is really
nice positive feedback when you put up a song or a video and you can
see that people are watching it or downloading it.</p>

<p><em>As a followup, do you have any idea which social network is most
 effective for the band ?</em></p>

<p>D: I think you&#8217;ve got to use what you&#8217;re comfortable with.</p>

<p>K: Exactly. I mean, I feel like Facebook&#8217;s pretty good for us, because
that&#8217;s where we&#8217;d all post anyway. It feels quite natural.</p>

<p>D: Myspace was never really our thing, I&#8217;m actually quite pleased to
see it fading away.  For twitter, I think I&#8217;m a bit more the businessy
side of the band, gig updates etc, whereas Kathryn just likes to chat
with people - I&#8217;m always jealous of how interesting and authentic her
Twitter feed is, I worry that mine is a bit cold&#8230;  Kathryn has
joined Google+ tho, which I&#8217;m resisting for the moment.  I&#8217;m trying to
minimise distractions of all kinds and go upstairs and do some mixing!</p>

<p><em>The band has a presence on every social network in the universe. When
 will you get a flipping account on identi.ca so all the freedom
 lovers can follow your antics ?</em></p>

<p>K: It&#8217;s funny. Identi.ca is something that&#8217;s been popping up lot
recently!</p>

<p>D: We go through phases of things, so once the album&#8217;s put to bed,
we&#8217;ll probably be reviewing our social networks and internet presence
- identi.ca will be top of the list, we promise.</p>

<p><em>I&#8217;ve read that collectively, the band is quite &#8216;impatient&#8217;. My
personal gut feeling is that you are also perfectionists - the type of
people who might argue for hours about the precise placement and
duration of a triangle being sounded.</em></p>

<p><em>Is this the case ? If so, how do you marry these two conflicting
 personality traits ?</em></p>

<p>K: This is a chillingly accurate gut feeling. We clearly aren&#8217;t
playing with our cards too close to our chests.</p>

<p>D: We do do everything ourselves, and we can get lost in tiny
recording details, or graphics for the website for far too long.  I
think the more we do, and the better musicians we feel we&#8217;re becoming,
the happier we are to just let the music do what it wants to do. We&#8217;ve
definitely tried to beat songs into shape, but when they&#8217;re working by
themselves, that&#8217;s the best way.</p>

<p><em>This is an awfully cliched interview question but then again I am an
 awful cliche - what bands were you all influenced by ?</em></p>

<p><em>I am aware Kathryn admires Ben Gibbard (Death Cab For Cutie) and
 likes Weezer and Clutch. What about Daniel ?</em></p>

<p>D: I think those are the bands that we all like together pretty
much. My early influences were bands like REM and Nirvana, as well as
more esoteric ones like They Might Be Giants and a fantastic German
punk band called Die Arzte.  We do divide duties a bit in the band,
where Kathryn is ultimately responsible for lyrics, though I do
occasionally throw words at her to freak her out, I&#8217;m the one who has
more responsibility for production.  It took me quite a long time to
work out where we wanted to be going, with our hard edged drums at one
end, and Kathryn&#8217;s subtle, elegant melodies at the other.  I found it
difficult to find bands that were doing what we wanted to be
doing. When I first got into Death Cab, back when Transatlanticism was
coming out, it was something that I just felt they were doing so well
- he&#8217;s an amazing lyricist, and Chris Walla&#8217;s production on those
albums is fantastic.</p>

<p><em>You are a band with strong principles and a sense of independence. I
 read with interest your post about being torn about having your music
 broadcast on a TV <a href="http://iamnotlefthanded.tumblr.com/post/4310895595/selling">advert</a>.</em></p>

<p><em>Can you elaborate about how that came about and the dilemma it
 presented to the band ?</em></p>

<p><em>What was the consensus amongst fans who gave you feedback ?</em></p>

<p>K: Everyone has been hands down positive.  I think we were more
conflicted than anyone else. I think everyone knows that the music
industry&#8217;s in pretty poor state and this gives us the freedom to spend
more time on music.  The company had actually used the same piece of
music for a much smaller ad in Spain, and they just really liked it,
so their Italian ad agency approached us when they had this new
campaign.  It wasn&#8217;t the worst dilemma. I mean it wasn&#8217;t for an ad for
cigarettes, or a puppy-strangling machine, we just wanted to make sure
we thought long and hard about the implications before we committed to
it.</p>

<p>Read part 2 of this interview with &#8216;I Am Not Lefthanded&#8217; -
&#8217;<a href="http://nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/ianl-this-is-now">This Is Now</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[interview with I Am Not Left Handed]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/interview-i-am-not-left-handed/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-12T12:09:16+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/interview-i-am-not-left-handed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&#8216;I Am Not Lefthanded&#8217; are a band who produce the most wonderful
music. The band are a three piece - mainly from Ireland - and the
lineup is:</p>

<ul>
<li>Kathryn - vocals, guitar, piano</li>
<li>Daniel - bass, vocals</li>
<li>Benji - drums</li>
</ul>


<p>&#8216;I Am Not Lefthanded&#8217; have released a couple of EP&#8217;s and are currently
putting the finishing touches to their first album - &#8216;The Fire And The
Sigh&#8217;.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s hard to categorise &#8216;I Am Not Lefthanded&#8217; but they produce
beautiful melodies with the most fantastic vocals and lyrics. The
band&#8217;s music and videos are available on their <a href="http://www.iamnotlefthanded.com/">site</a> so have a
listen and make your own mind up.</p>

<p>The band will be playing in London at Bush Hall on Friday 23 September
at <a href="http://iamnotlefthanded.tumblr.com/post/8729448258/new-show-announced-in-london-at-bush-hall-on-september">Bush Hall</a> in Shepherd&#8217;s Bush for an excellent cause.</p>

<p>I fell in love with the band&#8217;s music since I first heard them on <a href="http://danlynch.org/">Dan
Lynch</a>&#8217;s excellent <a href="http://ratholeradio.org/">Rathole Radio</a> podcast which showcases a
eclectic mix of Creative Commons music.</p>

<p>Since then, I&#8217;ve bought both EP&#8217;s in addition to some very stylish
IANL socks. I also managed to persuade Kathryn and Daniel to introduce
the new wonderful single &#8216;Alone&#8217; on <a href="http://notapodcast.tumblr.com/post/7378039423/6-get-your-cocs-out">episode 6</a> of the award
winning, legendary &#8217;<a href="http://notapodcast.tumblr.com/">This Is Not A Podcast</a>&#8217;.</p>

<p>Flushed, surprised and delighted by this achievement, I then chanced
my arm and asked Kathryn and Daniel if they would consider an
&#8216;interview&#8217; where I sent them miscellaneous random questions via email
which they would then scan and answer.</p>

<p>Needless to say - Kathryn and Daniel kindly acceded to my demands for
an interview - probably in an effort to rid themselves of this mad
stalker.</p>

<p>I was ecstatic that Kathryn and Daniel took time out of their busy
schedules to provide such detailed, lengthy, considered answers
(instead of quick, trite one-liners) and, hopefully, the &#8216;interview&#8217;
makes fascinating reading.</p>

<p>Anyway, combined with my inane ramblings, the final result is rather
long so I have split the interview into two parts:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/ianl-that-was-then">IANL - &#8216;That Was Then&#8217;</a></li>
<li><a href="http://nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/ianl-this-is-now">IANL - &#8216;This Is Now&#8217;</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Music - available by 2017]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/07/26/google-music-available-2017/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-26T11:07:05+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/07/26/google-music-available-2017</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks ago, I signed up for a invitation to Google Music. The
service is only available in the US but, by a lucky chance of fate, I
just happened to be connected to my corporate VPN so I was successful
and an invitation duly arrived in my Inbox.</p>

<p>Initially, the Google Music Manager software didn&#8217;t support Linux. Nor
was the Ogg Vorbis audio format supported so I didn&#8217;t pursue it any
further as both of these were show stoppers for me. I don&#8217;t intend
re-ripping my entire music collection to MP3 format.</p>

<p>However, last week, Google released a Linux version of Music Manager
and added
&#8217;<a href="http://www.google.com/support/music/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;answer=1100462&amp;topic=1100183">support</a>&#8217;
for Ogg format audio files. The &#8216;support&#8217; for the Ogg format is
slightly strange - Ogg audio files will be transcoded back to 320kps
MP3 files which represents a conversion from one lossy format to
another lossy format. Hopefully, in the longer term, there will be
true native support for Ogg.</p>

<p>Anyway, I downloaded the Music Manager software and started uploading
my music collection mainly so I could listen to music on my netbook
which currently runs <a href="http://chromeos.hexxeh.net/">Chromium OS</a>.</p>

<p>I started the upload 2 days ago and it&#8217;s been running during the
day. So far, it has managed to upload 505 songs out of a total 1,880
so it&#8217;s not exactly a speedy process.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the brave new world]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/07/21/welcome-brave-new-world/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-21T17:25:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/07/21/welcome-brave-new-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well - I lasted about 4 hours without a blog.</p>

<p>This latest incarnation is powered by Hyde.</p>

<p>This means I can write my posts in Markdown, generate and test the
site locally and then upload using &#8216;rsync&#8217;.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[humour on BBC breakfast]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/07/21/humour-bbc-breakfast/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-21T09:23:58+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/07/21/humour-bbc-breakfast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>BBC Breakfast ran a story this morning about the sale of
<a href="http://www.woodlands.co.uk/buying-a-wood/">woodlands</a>. The gentlemen
responsible for selling woodlands was quite a comedian. He started his
act with:</p>

<blockquote><p>&#8216;In these difficult economic times, people are looking to invest in
woodlands to hedge their bets&#8230;&#8217;</p></blockquote>

<p>and then, referring to the potential investment opportunity and
without a glimmer of a smile, he delivered the immaculate line</p>

<blockquote><p>&#8216;In a few years time, once the wood has matured, people will see
that you can get income from trees&#8217;.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[farewell Paul Scholes]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/05/31/farewell-paul-scholes/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-31T09:11:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/05/31/farewell-paul-scholes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/RD2bDI-AOBjwHYPgXVHS1w?feat=embedwebsite"><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-queZ1d_BoUs/TeSv7gEeUII/AAAAAAAABvE/7vhA7va4eyA/s800/Paul-Scholes-Manchester-United-Barcelona-Cham_2602915.jpg"
height="298" width="218"></a></p>

<p>One of my favourite United players - for his sublime skills on the
pitch and the modest, understated way he conducted himself off
it. Thanks for all the memories, Paul.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rob Daley RIP]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/05/28/rob-daley-rip/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-28T13:12:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/05/28/rob-daley-rip</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The ticket allocations for the London 2012 Olympics haven&#8217;t been
announced yet so I don&#8217;t know whether I&#8217;ll be watching Tom Daley
competing in the 10m platform diving semi final on 9th August.</p>

<p>If I do, I&#8217;ll be sparing a thought and probably shedding a quiet tear
for Tom Daley&#8217;s dad, Rob, who lost his 5 year battle against a brain
tumour yesterday.</p>

<p>Last year, I enjoyed a BBC documentary about Tom Daley where his Dad
interrupted a formal press conference to give his son a big hug,
thoroughly embarassing him in the process. You could just sense the
immense sense of love and pride Rob Daley had in his son.</p>

<p>Sadly, he will never get to see him compete at the London Olympics. 40
years old. Sometimes life just isn&#8217;t bloody fair.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[the joy of Markdown]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/05/17/joy-markdown/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-17T22:27:58+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/05/17/joy-markdown</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For many years, I have flitted between a plethora of different
blogging platforms mainly out of curiosity, boredom, frustration or
occasionally sheer bloody mindedness.</p>

<p>I have lost draft posts in WordPress, Tumblr, Posterous and Habari due
to network glitches, browser crashes, my own stupidity and a broken
AutoSave plugin.</p>

<p>One night in a lonely hotel room, the realisation suddenly dawned on
me that my frustration with all of these blogging platforms was that I
spent a lot of time in the post editor and none of the post editors
did what I wanted.</p>

<p>Whether you use Tumblr, Posterous, WordPress, Habari, Drupal, Movable
Type, Django-Mingus or another esoteric blog platform, you normally
find yourself composing content in a Web browser within a blank text
box writing raw HTML.</p>

<p>Alternatively, you might be using some WYSIWYG editor that helps you
insert the appropriate HTML tags.</p>

<p>There are a few things wrong with this scenario as far as I&#8217;m
concerned:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>I don&#8217;t particularly want or need to learn and remember HTML
tags. People ask why there&#8217;s a HTML reference card in the lavatory.</p></li>
<li><p>WYSIWYG editors can produce monstrous, bloated, ugly and sometimes,
as a bonus, invalid HTML.</p></li>
<li><p>I don&#8217;t really want to use a WYSIWYG editor. I have invested time
learning to scratch the surface of the functionality provided by the
one true editor - Emacs.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>After reading, but steadfastly ignoring multiple articles about
<a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax">Markdown</a> for
many months and making a mental note to investigate further, I finally
set aside 10 minutes to do so.</p>

<p>Without being over dramatic, Markdown has changed my life. For the
better.</p>

<p>Markdown is a markup language (&#8216;geddit ?&#8217;) that uses a easy to read
notation as shorthand for HTML.</p>

<p>The beauty of the Markdown syntax is that text written in the Markdown
format is perfectly readable. This makes reading, scanning, reviewing
and editing text much easier and quicker.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m a simple man with simple tastes so my blog posts primarily use
paragraphs, lists, hyperlinks and the very occasional image.</p>

<p>A hyperlink in Markdown looks like</p>

<pre><code>[Markdown](http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax)
</code></pre>

<p>A blank line indicates the end of a paragraph. Again, this is how we
compose text in emails and is so much more natural than</p>

<pre><code>&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>The HTML tags above are a preformatted block. In Markdown, this is
simply denoted by a 4 character indent.</p>

<p>To <em>emphasise</em> a word, you simply enclose the word in asterisk
characters which is what a lot of luddite, bearded Unix geeks tend to
do anyway. Using two asterisk characters will result in <strong>bold</strong> text.</p>

<p>Similarly, if you want to force a line break you simply append two
blank spaces to the end of a line.</p>

<p>Code blocks are introduced by a single quote.</p>

<p><code>   printf("Hello World\n");</code></p>

<p>Bulleted lists are introduced by a hypen or asterisk character so a
list of my favourite fruits would be written as:</p>

<pre><code>* Apples
* Oranges
* Pears
* Bananas
</code></pre>

<p>Ordered lists use numbers and look like, well, ordered lists.</p>

<pre><code>1. Giggs
2. Scholes
3. Cantona
</code></pre>

<p>Quotes are also easy and intuitive introduced by the &#8216;>&#8217; character.</p>

<blockquote><p>Are you still doing what you did 5 years ago ?<br/>
Yeah ? Well don&#8217;t make a career out of it.<br/>
Mark E. Smith (The Fall)</p></blockquote>

<p>Most blogging platforms either provides native Markdown support or has
plugins available to provide such functionality.</p>

<p>However, the real beauty of Markdown for me is that Emacs inevitably
has a powerful Markdown mode that provides font colouring, additional
menu shortcuts for the common constructs and a feature to examine the
generated HTML in an Emacs buffer or preview the results in a Web
browser.</p>

<p><a
href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/sykhGbfuwfI5NUo4vc_yTg?feat=embedwebsite"><img
src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_l2uGy1RGCiE/TdLzq1bo1dI/AAAAAAAABuk/ibt1UdW_VpY/s640/Markdown-Emacs.png"
height="640" width="614" /></a></p>

<p>This is incredibly useful for me as I can quickly check the generated HTML and even validate my blog posts. Validating my posts wasn&#8217;t easy before as the addition of the Disqus Javascript code generates a number of warnings from the W3C validator.</p>

<p><a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/grEBQVK_F7elXpEFtyQNEQ?feat=embedwebsite"><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_l2uGy1RGCiE/TdLz1_fNSxI/AAAAAAAABus/LksKcNKG7_Q/s640/Markdown-Preview.png" height="388" width="640" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[C grade student]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/04/24/c-grade-student/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-24T13:13:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/04/24/c-grade-student</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Chatting with a good friend over dinner last night, he recounted how
his son ambushed him late one Sunday night with some economics
homework that he&#8217;d somehow manage to overlook and which simply had to
be submitted the following morning.</p>

<p>Annoyed, and after dispensing a severe bollocking, he reluctantly sat
down and gave his son some lengthy help with the complex and thorny
topic of</p>

<blockquote><p>&#8216;How does monetary policy affect the economy ?&#8217;</p></blockquote>

<p>A week later, his son mumbled &#8216;Oh yeah - I got that Eco essay back
today and got a &#8216;C&#8217; for it&#8217;.</p>

<p>My friend has a first class honours degree in Economics from the
University of Warwick, has spent 26 years working in finance and
banking and is currently a senior economic analyst for the leading
fund manager, Gartmore.</p>

<p>My - how we laughed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[exciting times]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/03/03/exciting-times/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-03T10:07:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/03/03/exciting-times</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>These are indeed exciting times in the Brightside household:</p>

<ul>
<li>Norma Jeane will be taking part in the 125th Lawn Tennis
Championships to be held at
<a href="http://nbrightside.com/blog/2008/07/06/wimbledon-match-report">Wimbledon</a>
between 20 June and 3 July. Her precise role isn&#8217;t known yet but may
include &#8216;Waiting On (Silver Service)&#8217; - fawning over loud,
overbearing sales people out on a corporate jolly, &#8216;Bar staff&#8217;
(serving jugs of Pimms to middle aged Daily Mail readers) or
tantalisingly, &#8216;Courtesy car driver&#8217; (ferrying a morose
<a href="http://nbrightside.com/blog/2009/09/09/inside-the-mind-of-andy-murray">Andy Murray</a>
around). This represents a rapid promotion from her initial
placement two years ago, where she started out on &#8216;Litter collection
surrounding courts 10 and 11&#8217; before being promoted to &#8216;Housekeeping
duties&#8217; or, as she so eloquently put it - &#8216;Cleaning the bogs&#8217;.</li>
<li>Norma will be visiting Holloway prison in April. She claims this is
part of her District Nursing course but I have my doubts. She seems
to be watching a lot of those legal dramas recently and taking
copious notes.</li>
<li>Norman Junior III is recuperating from fracturing his right arm for
the second time. Note to self - any activity containing the word
&#8216;roller&#8217; that takes place on a concrete road is potentially
hazardous. He is soldiering on quite well and only needs assistance
with his socks. He has subsequently changed his XBox nickname to
&#8216;OneArmedBandit&#8217; and is experimenting using his toes to manipulate
the controller.</li>
<li>I had a brush with West Midlands traffic police last week in
Solihull after daring to consult a old fashioned map while
driving. After 15 minutes of being patronised by a fascist pig and
being forced to beg and scrape on bended knee, I managed to escape
with a verbal warning instead of the threatened &#8216;6 point penalty for
careless driving&#8217;. However, I am still puzzling over the &#8216;correct&#8217;
answer to the copper&#8217;s deep, probing question: &#8216;Sir, please could
you tell me why were you travelling at 25 miles per hour in a 30
zone ?&#8217;</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[why Arsenal lost the Carling Cup]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/03/01/why-arsenal-lost-carling-cup/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-01T11:42:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/03/01/why-arsenal-lost-carling-cup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I heard that Arsenal were busy making plans for their injured and
oh so inspirational captain, Cesc Fabregas, to hoist the trophy aloft
and end 6 barren years without a sniff of a trophy, I had a horrible
feeling it might end that way.</p>

<p>Can you imagine the suspended United captain, a grey suited Roy Keane,
doing that back in 1999 ? Can you even imagine Ferguson even
contemplating that option for just a second ? No. Neither can I.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
