<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tv | Blog In Isolation]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/categories/tv/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T20:07:32+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy C]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[humour on BBC breakfast]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/07/21/humour-bbc-breakfast/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-21T09:23:58+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/07/21/humour-bbc-breakfast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>BBC Breakfast ran a story this morning about the sale of
<a href="http://www.woodlands.co.uk/buying-a-wood/">woodlands</a>. The gentlemen
responsible for selling woodlands was quite a comedian. He started his
act with:</p>

<blockquote><p>'In these difficult economic times, people are looking to invest in
woodlands to hedge their bets...'</p></blockquote>

<p>and then, referring to the potential investment opportunity and
without a glimmer of a smile, he delivered the immaculate line</p>

<blockquote><p>'In a few years time, once the wood has matured, people will see
that you can get income from trees'.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[farewell Paul Scholes]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/05/31/farewell-paul-scholes/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-31T09:11:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/05/31/farewell-paul-scholes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/RD2bDI-AOBjwHYPgXVHS1w?feat=embedwebsite"><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-queZ1d_BoUs/TeSv7gEeUII/AAAAAAAABvE/7vhA7va4eyA/s800/Paul-Scholes-Manchester-United-Barcelona-Cham_2602915.jpg"
height="298" width="218"></a></p>

<p>One of my favourite United players - for his sublime skills on the
pitch and the modest, understated way he conducted himself off
it. Thanks for all the memories, Paul.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rene Carayol's clever approach to taxation]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2007/01/12/rene-carayols-clever-approach-to-taxation/"/>
    <updated>2007-01-12T19:42:37+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2007/01/12/rene-carayols-clever-approach-to-taxation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I also enjoyed last night's '<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/pressoffice/proginfo/tv/wk2/unplaced.shtml#unplaced_mortgage">Did they pay off their mortgage in two
years
?</a>'
about a likable creative artist from Cornwall who makes interesting,
arty (and high margin) stoves from VW car parts aimed at rich people
in South Kensington.</p>

<p>The last minute of the
<a href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2006/01/20/recursive-financial-advice-from-the-bbc/">show</a>
was a real emotional roller coaster.</p>

<p>Firstly, I was delighted to hear the couple's hard work had showed an
unbelievable return of &pound;104,000 profit but then shattered to
hear they had fallen a paltry &pound;1,500 of being able to pay off
their mortgage in full.</p>

<p>My hopes rose again as 'international businessman and motivational
speaker, Rene Carayol' spontaneously (and very conveniently) purchased
a stove and handed them the &pound;1,500 in cash.</p>

<p>Then I started to laugh uncontrollably as I struggled to assimilate
Rene's closing words</p>

<blockquote><p>'Congratulations. You have done it. You have paid your mortgage off.
Now there's just one more small thing to do. Review the books and
see > how much you owe the tax man.'</p></blockquote>

<p>So, although they paid their mortgage off, the couple are now saddled
with a sizable personal loan to clear their debts to the Inland
Revenue.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The curious case of Patrick Gibson]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/11/09/the-curious-case-of-patrick-gibson/"/>
    <updated>2005-11-09T15:41:26+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/11/09/the-curious-case-of-patrick-gibson</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What would you do with 1 million GBP ?</p>

<p>Would you buy a mansion, a yacht and a Ferrari, give up your job, go
on holiday, donate it all to charity, buy your parents a new house,
take over your local football club or get U2 to play at your son's
birthday party ?</p>

<p>Don't worry - I haven't succumbed to the lure of '1001 subjects to
blog about' for people with vacuous brains.</p>

<p>This was precisely the quandry facing Patrick Gibson in 2004 when he
scooped the top prize of 1 million pounds on the ITV show 'Who wants
to be a Millionaire'.</p>

<p>Anyway, Patrick chose to buy the complete Iain Banks' books catalogue
together with DVD's of Quentin Tarantino's films and every single
episode of Channel 4's hilarious TV comedy 'Father Ted'. The reason
was that these were to be Patrick's specialist subjects for BBC's
Mastermind quiz.</p>

<p>Don't laugh - Patrick was crowned Mastermind of Great Brtain on last
night's enthralling show ! Even better, the narrow victory for the
Irish software developer prevented an Australian gentleman hoisting
the impressive, crystal glass fruit bowl aloft.</p>

<p>Another crushing defeat for the Aussies - oh dear.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Historic Moments]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/09/28/historic-moments/"/>
    <updated>2005-09-28T18:03:43+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/09/28/historic-moments</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There was an interesting program on ITV last night called <a href="http://www.itn-theshot.com/">The Shot
That Shook The World</a> about photographs
of historic moments.</p>

<h2>9/11</h2>

<p>Mesmeric, tragic, horrific and yet somehow those images are always
compelling. I guess this was the JFK moment for my generation where
everyone can remember exactly where they were and what they were
doing.</p>

<p>I was working for a small Internet company and a colleague was idly
surfing and memorably announced 'A plane has just hit the World Trade
Centre'. The internet soon ground to a halt and we watched the tragedy
unfold on portable TV in disbelief.</p>

<p>I remember early editions of an English newspaper carried photographs
of two people holding hands jumping to their deaths that were
subsequently pulled when they realised that this was real people in
real life with real mothers, fathers, brothers, sisters, sons and
daughters.</p>

<h2>Sport</h2>

<p>The Brazil goal against Italy in the 1970 World Cup. My favourite goal
of all time. The way Pele flicks the ball to Carlos Alberto. Pure art.</p>

<h2>Moon Landing (1969)</h2>

<p>I remember the whole school being assembled in the hall to watch these
grainy images on a black and white TV.</p>

<h2>Challenger disaster</h2>

<p>I visited the Kennedy Centre a few years ago and there is a nice,
simple, understated black
<a href="http://www.kennedyspacecenter.com/visitKSC/attractions/memorial.asp">memorial</a>
to all the astronauts who have lost their lives during the space
program. Ironically, one was killed in a car crash.</p>

<h2>Concorde crash</h2>

<p>Interesting as this footage was shot by a member of the public from a
moving car. This is much more prevalent now with the widespread use
camera phones which provided almost immediate access to photos of the
London bombings in July 2005.</p>

<h2>Hillsborough</h2>

<p>This wasn't actually featured but those photographs on the front page
of The Independent newspaper of ordinary people dying, squashed
against the railings in the Leppings Lane terrace at a football match
in Sheffield had a big effect on me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
