<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: music | Blog In Isolation]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/categories/music/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T20:07:32+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy C]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Am Not Left Handed - This Is Now]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/ianl-this-is-now/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-12T12:20:27+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/ianl-this-is-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is part 2 of an interview with Kathryn and Daniel from 'I Am Not
Left Handed'. The first part 'That Was Then' is available
<a href="http://nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/ianl-that-was-then">here</a>.</p>

<p><em>This might seem like (another) weird question but then again I am
slightly weird myself. I realise you're a relatively young band but
are they any songs of your own that you don't like and would not
contemplate playing live ? Maybe early songs that you have now
outgrown. Or are you fiercely proud of everything you've ever produced
?</em></p>

<p><em>I mean everyone has songs by their favourite bands that they can't
 stand.  For example, I love R.E.M but simply can not stand 'Losing My
 Religion'.</em></p>

<p><em>I'm not articulating this very well - I guess I'm thinking of when
Kurt used to get completely fed up with endless requests for 'Smells
Like Teen Spirit'.</em></p>

<p>D: I don't know that we feel relatively young!  Making decent music
takes time, we've years of unfocused songs and struggling bands behind
us.  I think as we get better at it, and letting the songs flow more
naturally, we're happier with the end result.  Kathryn definitely has
very high standards, she won't let us even record something that she's
not 100% behind, whereas I tend to be a bit more of the attitude, oh
we can just tinker with it a bit.  There are one or two songs that
I've forced a bit more, and as a result they just haven't had the same
staying power - 'Falling' from Yes Means No is one of those, we don't
ever play it live anymore.</p>

<p>K: Though who knows, maybe it's just waiting for us to come and
rewrite it... we do end up doing that a lot.</p>

<p><em>Mind you, I call you a young band but I saw an interview with you in
 July 2009 when you talk of gigs, videos and songs, so when exactly
 did you actually form ?</em></p>

<p>D: As I say, Kathryn and I have been doing this for a few years, in
different iterations but I think the end of 2007 was when we really
worked out where we were going and added Benji - we had another
guitarist who left, and it really made us have to sit down and rewrite
all of our songs as a three-piece, which was the best thing that ever
happened to us.</p>

<p><em>OK - which of the following appear on your iPod/turntable/cassette player ?</em>
<em></p>

<ul>
    <li>Idlewild</li>
    <li>Nirvana</li>
    <li>R.E.M.</li>
    <li>The Duke Spirit</li>
    <li>The Fall</li>
    <li>The National</li>
    <li>The Smiths</li>
    <li>The Chameleons (who ?)</li>
</ul>


<p></em></p>

<p>D: A little Idlewild, a fair amount of Nirvana.  I've done sound for
the Duke Spirit but don't have any of their recordings.  The Fall not
at all, The National I keep hearing about, but I haven't managed to
get into them despite a couple of casual listenings. The
Smiths... let's just say I'm a big fan of Johnny Marr, less so of the
rest of the band.  No idea about the Chameleons, sorry.</p>

<p>K: I have plenty Idlewild, Nirvana, R.E.M, Duke Spirit and even The
Chameleons. None of the Fall, the National and definitely not the
Smiths. Marr is great but I find Morrissey just too pretentious. Take
that comment about the killings in Norway being nothing compared to
the number of animals killed for KFC and McDonalds every day. Every
time he puts out a quote I just think - I have absolutely nothing in
common with your way of thinking.</p>

<p><em>You've covered 'Lousy Reputation' by 'We Are Scientists' and 'I Will
 Follow You Into The Dark' by 'Death Cab For Cutie'. What other songs
 have you covered ? Or soundcheck to ?</em></p>

<p>K: We always had a policy from the beginning of only playing our own
material, and not covering other people's songs.  I think we'd heard
too many other bands in Dublin who'd include a cover in their set, and
at the end, that's all that people would remember.</p>

<p>D: But as we've become more confident in our sound, we're loosening
that up a little.  In a different band, we did used to play a mixed-up
version of 'Where Is My Mind?', with Kathryn on drums.  We're toying
with a cover of a <a href="http://www.therapyquestionmark.co.uk/">Therapy?</a> song at the moment, the
harmonies are really nice, we're just trying to get it to work
instrumentally.</p>

<p><em>Are you all those sickening self-taught people who can play a song
back perfectly seconds after listening to it ? Or did you have any
formal music tuition ?</em></p>

<p>D: I'm very much from a classical music background, I played the viola
for years, but never really found it that satisfying - I do think the
classical education system with its focus more on reading music rather
than listening is a much poorer way to learn. Since I started playing
guitar and bass in my teens, I've found it a lot more enjoyable, just
playing by feel and with what sounds good, and essentially trying to
forget how to read music.  I do get jealous of Kathryn sometimes,
she's a far better ear for harmonies and sense of rhythm than me. Then
again, she keeps me on my toes and makes me up my game, so it's not
all bad!</p>

<p><em>When recording the new album, it appeared you hired a big house in
the country with a studio so you were able to live together while
recording ?</em></p>

<p><em>Did this help and accelerate the creative process or did it ever get
 claustrophobic ?</em></p>

<p>K: It's a medium-sized house in the very beautiful surroundings of
Northamptonshire.  We've been in and out of London reasonably
regularly too, so it hasn't been complete isolation, which I think is
good in the sanity stakes.  It's a great place though, there's horses
out one window, a river at the bottom of the garden and a graveyard
next door to keep an eye on us. Sometimes the local kids go there to
make out. That's about as uncomfortable as it gets though.</p>

<p>D: We've put the studio together ourselves.  It's been so great to
actually have the space to make and record the music properly, with a
proper live room and control room, it's really been a fertile time for
us in terms of writing new songs - the hard bit is finishing them,
we've a lot of new things we like, but trying to coax them into a
recordable shape is trickier.</p>

<p><em>Now we turn to face the future. You finished recording the new album
 'The Fire And The Sigh' a few weeks ago. Is a release date imminent
 ?</em></p>

<p>D: Not quite finished yet!  I think we were initially trying to
release some singles ahead of the album, so we worked hard on Alone
and put it out. But as we've progressed, we just want to make sure the
album is complete and everything's as perfect as it can be before we
put anything else out.  So you won't hear any more until it's all
perfect.</p>

<p>K: The end of August is D-Day, but then there's mastering and artwork
and more videos to worry about, so it'll be another couple of
months. All the advice we've had is that indie bands tend to rush
their releases, and it all comes out in a muddle.  This is a big
statement for us, so we want to make sure everything's right before it
goes out in the world.</p>

<p><em>Oh I nearly forgot - what is the origin of the name - 'The Fire And
 The Sigh' ?</em></p>

<p>D: I like album titles that are lines from a song on the album, almost
as much as I hate album titles that are the same as one of the song
titles, I think that's just lazy.  I don't know about the others, but
layout: post
comments: true
for me, The Fire &amp; The Sigh really sums up the tone of Kathryn's
writing, I think she writes about things that make her angry or
melancholy. I can see Kathryn laughing as I'm saying this, but that's
how it seems to me!</p>

<p>K: I'm only laughing a little bit...</p>

<p><em>I just love 'The Place That Won't Take Me Back'. I'm almost reluctant
 to ask this as I firmly believe you don't really want or need to know
 what the lyrics are about. It's much better left to your
 imagination.</em></p>

<p><em>I remember when I discovered that 'The Geese of Beverley Road' by The
 National was actually about ruffians setting off car alarms. I was
 distraught for 5 days.</em></p>

<p><em>So, although it's fraught with danger, could you describe what the
 'The Place...' is about ?</em></p>

<p>K: I've kept a couple of blogs over the years. I'm sort of dodging
this question for fear of ruining the song for you now, but there are
two posts I can think of, that were about how I write songs. They
might help make up for not answering.</p>

<p>One here:
<a href="http://wealthvsfame.wordpress.com/2010/01/17/its-only-time">http://wealthvsfame.wordpress.com/2010/01/17/its-only-time</a></p>

<p>And one about how it's probably more obvious an answer than it would
have been in an older song here:
<a href="http://www.iamnotlefthanded.com/listen.html">http://www.iamnotlefthanded.com/listen.html</a></p>

<p><em>Glastonbury has just been and gone. So has Bono. Do you like
 festivals ? Any plans to appear in any this summer ?</em></p>

<p>D: Festivals are okay, I did go to 29 one summer when I was working
with the Rumble Strips, which I think burned me out on them a
little. Playing at festivals, it can be hard to get a real rapport
with the crowd, we like things a bit more intimate where you can have
a back and forth with people.  Because of the recording, we've not
been applying for festivals this summer, we may find one or two next
year that we like.</p>

<p><em>Can you believe Larry Mullen Jnr is 49 years old ? He looks about
 19.</em></p>

<p>D: He's always been consistently youthful, he looks like he could join
up with Westlife any minute... I think the rest of U2 may have been
keeping him in a freezer between shows.  By the way, I'm not an ardent
supporter of U2, but if you haven't recently, go back and watch the
video to Elevation.  The Edge is hilarious.</p>

<p>K: It's funny you should mention this. I wasn't so big a fan of U2
until I saw them live at Slane Castle back in 2001. Over the whole
day, I'd sneaked from the very back of the crowd to the very front (it
pays to be tiny at most gigs - unless it's an Audioslave show, though
that's a whole other story) And just as the drums kicked in I was hit
by this wall of sound.  And it was like nothing I'd ever heard
before. 'Where The Streets Have No Name' still stands as the best song
I've ever heard live.</p>

<p>Conversely, my home town is the only place that U2 have officially
said they'll never play again. When they had one of their first gigs
there back in the late 70s, the crowd threw pennies at them til they
got off stage. Whoops. No accounting for taste I suppose.</p>

<p><em>'Lifelines' seems a pretty dark love song - 'No more talks of who let
 who down'.</em></p>

<p>K: A dark lovesong to friendship after a break-up, is probably closer
to the truth. I wrote a blogpost recently that sort of relates, if you
think anyone's curious. The post isn't about Lifelines, but it's on a
similar theme</p>

<p><a href="http://everythingbuttheocean.tumblr.com/post/8608907557/happy-endings">http://everythingbuttheocean.tumblr.com/post/8608907557/happy-endings</a></p>

<p><em>I love the new single 'Alone'. This song first appeared as a 75
 second tune on the 'Time To Leave' EP and was embellished to evolve
 into a fully fledged 4 mins 30 second perfect pop song complete with
 a homemade zombie video.</em></p>

<p><em>Did you always intend to develop the song in this way ? Was the EP
 version just a taster ?</em></p>

<p>D: It's kind of representative of the way we write - things tend to
hang around as shortened versions for quite a while, until something
else occurs to us and it takes a new direction.  I think Kathryn had
written it about 2 days before we recorded it for 'Time To Leave'. The
same happened with 'Boats' on 'Yes Means No'...</p>

<p>Wonderful IANL quote from <a href="http://www.thebandwagontv.com/?p=302">bandwagon</a></p>

<blockquote><p>'We don't play pop music, we don't write music for art's sake, we
don't represent any movements, we're not hip, we're not cutting
edge, we don't dress to be cool. We do manage ourselves, we write
our own songs, we do our own recordings, we shoot our own videos, we
design our own covers, we made our own website. We're not generally
negative people, oh yes, and we're not lefthanded.'</p></blockquote>

<p><em>OK - final question.</em></p>

<p><em>What plans, hopes, ambitions does the band have for the rest of 2011
 and into 2012 ?</em></p>

<p>D: The big plan is to get the album out.  We're so excited to finally
be making a full-length statement.  A lot of people are saying that
the 40 minute album is dead as a concept, that singles are the way of
the future, but I think there's very much something to be said for
sitting down and listening to an album through for 40 minutes.  It's
the length of the human attention span, at least that's what they told
us in school as we had 40 minute lessons.</p>

<p>K: At the moment, we are focused on finishing the recording, so we're
trying not to put too many plans in place until everything's
ready. Another US tour is definitely on the cards, and hopefully some
Canadian dates too.  We'll be back to Ireland as well, for the Irish
release and in the medium term, we really want to get to some of
continental Europe: Spain, Germany and the Netherlands in
particular. I think we'll just have to see where the wind blows us -
we ended up touring the last EP for two years, so we'll just have to
see how the album does, and where people want us to come and play.</p>

<p>D: We are hoping to start doing a regular internet show tho, maybe
once a month - in some ways we feel like our home town is online these
days, more so than Dublin or London, so if we can connect with people
there, so much the better! We've some video ideas we're excited about
making too, we're just trying to keep on the straight and narrow for
this last stretch.  We are letting ourselves out for one London show
in September - it's for a fantastic children's charity.  It's in Bush
Hall, on the 23rd of September.  Details as always are on the website
at: <a href="http://www.iamnotlefthanded.com">www.iamnotlefthanded.com</a></p>

<p><em>Many thanks for your time and all the best.</em></p>

<p>D: Thanks for all the thoughtful, wide-ranging questions.  I always
enjoy having the time to answer interviews like this, it makes me get
my head in order - the act of writing things down means you have to
commit to positions on things you may not have forced yourself to
decide about until now.</p>

<p>K: Just so :) It's been a pleasure.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Am Not Left Handed - That Was Then]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/ianl-that-was-then/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-12T12:18:42+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/ianl-that-was-then</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>OK - let's get the boring stuff out of the way.</em></p>

<p><em>How did you all meet and form the band ? Please don't tell me you
posted an ad in 'Melody Maker'.</em></p>

<p>D: Kathryn and I met in Dublin, we were working on a summer course
together.  We both played in different bands at the time, I was
fronting my own band, Coyote Blue, and Kathryn was playing keys and
singing backing vocals with some friends of hers.  We'd been staying
up late at night with the other counsellors, a few of whom were
musicians too, and there were guitars floating around, but Kathryn
kept refusing any chance to accept the guitar and play a song.</p>

<p>I knew that she was musical through some conversations we'd had
before, so eventually I persuaded her to sneak away to a different
room.  After playing several songs at her, and relentless asking, she
eventually surrendered and played me a song.  I was blown away, and
just knew right then that she should be playing her own music.</p>

<p>We played with a couple of different line-ups in Dublin together,
before parting for a while.  Kathryn went to California and I moved to
London. I was working in the Camden Barfly with Benji.  We used to do
every Friday night, I was doing sound, he was stage managing.  With
six bands a night, doing 13-hour shifts, it was pretty much life in
the trenches - after a couple of years when Kathryn came over to
London, Benji was the only choice for a drummer, we've never regretted
it for a moment.</p>

<p><em>The Irish are well known for their love of music. Did music play a
big part in your childhood ?  Were you dragged into the pub every
Saturday night to play the bodhrán by your Father's side ?</em></p>

<p>K: Not so much with the bodhrán on Saturday nights, but one of my
earliest memories was after Mass on Sunday mornings, we used to go to
a pub on the river, just down the road from the church. This great
band played there every weekend, everything from soul to country. They
had a full brass section and this amazing guitarist with the fastest
fingers.</p>

<p>Later on, we got a piano in the house and dad used to sit beside me,
playing songs I still don't know the names of, and saying the chords
so I could play along. So I seem to have inherited my dad's knack for
playing by ear, but am completely rubbish at reading sheet music.</p>

<p>D: I think Kathryn had a more authentic Irish childhood.  I was raised
in Belfast, before moving to Dublin, and even then my family were of a
Church of Ireland background rather than the traditional Irish
Catholic.  So I was actually raised with classical music, playing the
viola in youth orchestras and such.  My father might not know a
Bodhrán if he saw one...</p>

<p><em>You announced that you all 'quit your jobs' in August 2010 to focus
 solely on the band. What did you both do before you were rock stars
 ?</em></p>

<p>K: We did quit our jobs last August to go on tour in the US. I worked
in film production, which means I spend most of my work day secretly
coming up with ideas for our next video, and stealing ideas as to how
we can make them on a low budget.</p>

<p>D: I worked as a touring sound engineer, with bands like the Young
Knives, The Rumble Strips and Blood Red Shoes.  It's not an easy
business making money just from music these days, so we still do a bit
of work on the side to make sure we still have a roof over our heads
while we're finishing the album.</p>

<p>K: I think the balance used to be about two thirds of our time
working, one third being in a band and now it's reversed.  Hopefully
as the band grows, we'll be able to drop that last third completely.</p>

<p><em>And what did your Mummies say when they heard your decision ?</em></p>

<p>K: Mum was supportive. Lots of comments about how I'd been working too
hard, and wouldn't this be a good time to write a book while we were
on the road. I suspect if they ever made a movie of the band's
adventures, it would be more of a feel-good comedy and less of a
gritty drama.</p>

<p>D: I'm the middle of three boys, and have a very awesome older brother
who works for the International Red Cross, really fulfilling most
everything my parents could want from a son.  I think they resigned
themselves a long while ago to the fact that I'm going to do what I'm
going to do.  They're just happy I'm not in jail or on the streets...</p>

<p><em>I've never been in a band, I can't play a note and I can't
sing. However, none of this stops me from being acutely interested in
the song writing process.</em></p>

<p><em>A couple of my favourite bands, R.E.M. and Nirvana, appear to write
 the music and then overlay random snippets of scribbled lyrics from
 notebooks.</em></p>

<p><em>I get the impression you don't operate this way and you write short
 stories - poems almost - that are then set to music.</em></p>

<p><em>Could you describe how the band produces music ?</em></p>

<p>D: In the early days, it used to be more the case that one or the
other of us would write a song alone, mainly Kathryn, and then it
would be brought to the band for development of the music.  Nowadays
most of our songwriting comes out of the two of us playing together.</p>

<p>K: We'll just get a spark of something - the guitar and bass at the
start of 'Boats' is a good example, we were just playing those chords
and they sounded... right, I guess is the best description.</p>

<p>D: Then when we have something we like, Kathryn'll work out a vocal
melody, and then we bring it to Benji.  He's our representation of the
world - if it works for him, if he can play something awesome with it,
it's a good song.  If not, it's back to the drawing board.  Finalised
lyrics tend to come at the very end.</p>

<p>K: We're not one of those bands who write songs in twelve minutes. It
can take anything up to a year of having a few bars of something
before it's ready to be turned into a full song.</p>

<p><em>Why are the <a href="http://iamnotlefthanded.tumblr.com/post/863604483/thing-a-week-21-alone-live">videos</a> from the early Camden sessions 'Private'
 ?</em></p>

<p>D: I think, earlier this year we wanted to clean-up our YouTube stream
- we wanted to just present the best material we have.</p>

<p>K: We can get a bit nitpicky over our own performances. They were
recordings we did quite fast for our Thing A Week last year, they were
fun to do at the time, but we didn't always think we were doing
ourselves justice in the long-term.</p>

<p><em>Robbie Williams never managed to 'break' American despite being
 successful in Europe and having the multi-million pound backing of
 EMI. Yet you have already toured America !</em></p>

<p><em>Why is that ? Is it because Daniel's view of the band's music as
 'American Indie' means your music is well received there ? Or did you
 just fancy a trip to DisneyLand ?</em></p>

<p>D: A large part of it is that I think we don't resonate so well in the
UK. We do have several lovely supporters here, but we don't fit into
the standard UK indie scene, so it's been a struggle trying to find
our own way.  We just kept getting a lot of requests from people to
come playing in the US, and we always like to go where we're invited.</p>

<p>K: At the moment, we're thinking about moving to San Francisco for a
while to see how being based in the US would work for us.  It's so
great that With the internet these days, location becomes less
relevant - we can still keep up with everyone online and spread our
music, no matter where we are in the world.</p>

<p><em>I was very interested to read that you manged to <a href="http://iamnotlefthanded.tumblr.com/post/1181380920/financed-where-we-go-from-here">raise</a>
 $11,000 funding using crowd sourcing on slicethepie.com as opposed to
 a lucrative record deal. How did that come about ?</em></p>

<p>K: The great thing with SliceThePie, is that it's one site where you
could put up the music and get it listened to and reviewed completely
anonymously by strangers.  The people they select for their showcase
are the people who get ranked the highest in this blind reviewing.  So
when we were put into the showcase last January, we knew that we'd
earned our place, purely because of the music.  It was a great
affirmation for ourselves, as much as anything.  Of course when we
were in the showcase we had to work our asses off and hustle and try
and encourage people to invest - which they did!  We hit our total in
September and since then we've been writing, rehearsing, setting up
the studio and recording.  We're coming into the final stretch now,
just want to make sure everything's as strong as it can be.  It's been
a slow process this year, we've been learning a lot about how to
record an album as much as writing one.</p>

<p>D: The SliceThePie thing came about in a really nice way actually. The
whole industry's pretty confused at the moment, record labels really
are not investing in young bands at all - you need to prove you're
having decent success on your own before they'll touch you.  At the
same time, there are a million different websites, promising you
everything from songwriting competitions, to festival slots, to gear
and cash prizes.  The problem with most of these, and one thing we
hate with a passion, is that they all involve getting bands to tell
their friends to sign-up and vote for them.  They're basically just
using bands to advertise their websites or products.  Music for us is
not a popularity contest, it's all about the one-on-one connection
that you make with a song.  Just because you might like our music, the
last thing we want you to do is sign up for something and get
subjected to spam and advertising.  The only thing we ask from our
fans is that if they like the music, then share it with their friends.</p>

<p><em>You use Tumblr for your blog. You use Feedburner. You use Google
 Analytics. You use Twitter. You have created your own Web site. Come
 on, own up - who's the geeky one in the band ?</em></p>

<p>K: We... probably both slightly geeky, though we've never thought of
ourselves that way.  It just makes sense to use the best tools
available, and we have been doing this a while, so we've tried a lot
of things over the years.</p>

<p><em>And does this individual torture themselves monitoring downloads,
 page views, sales and tweets on an hourly basis ?</em></p>

<p>D: Sales are always nice to know about...  The rest is useful,
particularly when you have information about where in the world people
are coming from etc.  It's not worth obsessing over, but it is really
nice positive feedback when you put up a song or a video and you can
see that people are watching it or downloading it.</p>

<p><em>As a followup, do you have any idea which social network is most
 effective for the band ?</em></p>

<p>D: I think you've got to use what you're comfortable with.</p>

<p>K: Exactly. I mean, I feel like Facebook's pretty good for us, because
that's where we'd all post anyway. It feels quite natural.</p>

<p>D: Myspace was never really our thing, I'm actually quite pleased to
see it fading away.  For twitter, I think I'm a bit more the businessy
side of the band, gig updates etc, whereas Kathryn just likes to chat
with people - I'm always jealous of how interesting and authentic her
Twitter feed is, I worry that mine is a bit cold...  Kathryn has
joined Google+ tho, which I'm resisting for the moment.  I'm trying to
minimise distractions of all kinds and go upstairs and do some mixing!</p>

<p><em>The band has a presence on every social network in the universe. When
 will you get a flipping account on identi.ca so all the freedom
 lovers can follow your antics ?</em></p>

<p>K: It's funny. Identi.ca is something that's been popping up lot
recently!</p>

<p>D: We go through phases of things, so once the album's put to bed,
we'll probably be reviewing our social networks and internet presence
- identi.ca will be top of the list, we promise.</p>

<p><em>I've read that collectively, the band is quite 'impatient'. My
personal gut feeling is that you are also perfectionists - the type of
people who might argue for hours about the precise placement and
duration of a triangle being sounded.</em></p>

<p><em>Is this the case ? If so, how do you marry these two conflicting
 personality traits ?</em></p>

<p>K: This is a chillingly accurate gut feeling. We clearly aren't
playing with our cards too close to our chests.</p>

<p>D: We do do everything ourselves, and we can get lost in tiny
recording details, or graphics for the website for far too long.  I
think the more we do, and the better musicians we feel we're becoming,
the happier we are to just let the music do what it wants to do. We've
definitely tried to beat songs into shape, but when they're working by
themselves, that's the best way.</p>

<p><em>This is an awfully cliched interview question but then again I am an
 awful cliche - what bands were you all influenced by ?</em></p>

<p><em>I am aware Kathryn admires Ben Gibbard (Death Cab For Cutie) and
 likes Weezer and Clutch. What about Daniel ?</em></p>

<p>D: I think those are the bands that we all like together pretty
much. My early influences were bands like REM and Nirvana, as well as
more esoteric ones like They Might Be Giants and a fantastic German
punk band called Die Arzte.  We do divide duties a bit in the band,
where Kathryn is ultimately responsible for lyrics, though I do
occasionally throw words at her to freak her out, I'm the one who has
more responsibility for production.  It took me quite a long time to
work out where we wanted to be going, with our hard edged drums at one
end, and Kathryn's subtle, elegant melodies at the other.  I found it
difficult to find bands that were doing what we wanted to be
doing. When I first got into Death Cab, back when Transatlanticism was
coming out, it was something that I just felt they were doing so well
- he's an amazing lyricist, and Chris Walla's production on those
albums is fantastic.</p>

<p><em>You are a band with strong principles and a sense of independence. I
 read with interest your post about being torn about having your music
 broadcast on a TV <a href="http://iamnotlefthanded.tumblr.com/post/4310895595/selling">advert</a>.</em></p>

<p><em>Can you elaborate about how that came about and the dilemma it
 presented to the band ?</em></p>

<p><em>What was the consensus amongst fans who gave you feedback ?</em></p>

<p>K: Everyone has been hands down positive.  I think we were more
conflicted than anyone else. I think everyone knows that the music
industry's in pretty poor state and this gives us the freedom to spend
more time on music.  The company had actually used the same piece of
music for a much smaller ad in Spain, and they just really liked it,
so their Italian ad agency approached us when they had this new
campaign.  It wasn't the worst dilemma. I mean it wasn't for an ad for
cigarettes, or a puppy-strangling machine, we just wanted to make sure
we thought long and hard about the implications before we committed to
it.</p>

<p>Read part 2 of this interview with 'I Am Not Lefthanded' -
'<a href="http://nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/ianl-this-is-now">This Is Now</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[interview with I Am Not Left Handed]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/interview-i-am-not-left-handed/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-12T12:09:16+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/interview-i-am-not-left-handed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>'I Am Not Lefthanded' are a band who produce the most wonderful
music. The band are a three piece - mainly from Ireland - and the
lineup is:</p>

<ul>
<li>Kathryn - vocals, guitar, piano</li>
<li>Daniel - bass, vocals</li>
<li>Benji - drums</li>
</ul>


<p>'I Am Not Lefthanded' have released a couple of EP's and are currently
putting the finishing touches to their first album - 'The Fire And The
Sigh'.</p>

<p>It's hard to categorise 'I Am Not Lefthanded' but they produce
beautiful melodies with the most fantastic vocals and lyrics. The
band's music and videos are available on their <a href="http://www.iamnotlefthanded.com/">site</a> so have a
listen and make your own mind up.</p>

<p>The band will be playing in London at Bush Hall on Friday 23 September
at <a href="http://iamnotlefthanded.tumblr.com/post/8729448258/new-show-announced-in-london-at-bush-hall-on-september">Bush Hall</a> in Shepherd's Bush for an excellent cause.</p>

<p>I fell in love with the band's music since I first heard them on <a href="http://danlynch.org/">Dan
Lynch</a>'s excellent <a href="http://ratholeradio.org/">Rathole Radio</a> podcast which showcases a
eclectic mix of Creative Commons music.</p>

<p>Since then, I've bought both EP's in addition to some very stylish
IANL socks. I also managed to persuade Kathryn and Daniel to introduce
the new wonderful single 'Alone' on <a href="http://notapodcast.tumblr.com/post/7378039423/6-get-your-cocs-out">episode 6</a> of the award
winning, legendary '<a href="http://notapodcast.tumblr.com/">This Is Not A Podcast</a>'.</p>

<p>Flushed, surprised and delighted by this achievement, I then chanced
my arm and asked Kathryn and Daniel if they would consider an
'interview' where I sent them miscellaneous random questions via email
which they would then scan and answer.</p>

<p>Needless to say - Kathryn and Daniel kindly acceded to my demands for
an interview - probably in an effort to rid themselves of this mad
stalker.</p>

<p>I was ecstatic that Kathryn and Daniel took time out of their busy
schedules to provide such detailed, lengthy, considered answers
(instead of quick, trite one-liners) and, hopefully, the 'interview'
makes fascinating reading.</p>

<p>Anyway, combined with my inane ramblings, the final result is rather
long so I have split the interview into two parts:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/ianl-that-was-then">IANL - 'That Was Then'</a></li>
<li><a href="http://nbrightside.com/blog/2011/08/12/ianl-this-is-now">IANL - 'This Is Now'</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Music - available by 2017]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/07/26/google-music-available-2017/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-26T11:07:05+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/07/26/google-music-available-2017</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks ago, I signed up for a invitation to Google Music. The
service is only available in the US but, by a lucky chance of fate, I
just happened to be connected to my corporate VPN so I was successful
and an invitation duly arrived in my Inbox.</p>

<p>Initially, the Google Music Manager software didn't support Linux. Nor
was the Ogg Vorbis audio format supported so I didn't pursue it any
further as both of these were show stoppers for me. I don't intend
re-ripping my entire music collection to MP3 format.</p>

<p>However, last week, Google released a Linux version of Music Manager
and added
'<a href="http://www.google.com/support/music/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;answer=1100462&amp;topic=1100183">support</a>'
for Ogg format audio files. The 'support' for the Ogg format is
slightly strange - Ogg audio files will be transcoded back to 320kps
MP3 files which represents a conversion from one lossy format to
another lossy format. Hopefully, in the longer term, there will be
true native support for Ogg.</p>

<p>Anyway, I downloaded the Music Manager software and started uploading
my music collection mainly so I could listen to music on my netbook
which currently runs <a href="http://chromeos.hexxeh.net/">Chromium OS</a>.</p>

<p>I started the upload 2 days ago and it's been running during the
day. So far, it has managed to upload 505 songs out of a total 1,880
so it's not exactly a speedy process.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[waiting for The National]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/12/08/waiting-for-the-national/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-08T13:26:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/12/08/waiting-for-the-national</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week, I went to see The National at Brixton Academy. Twice. Both
shows were great (Monday just shaded it) and the band resurrected a
rarely played classic ‘Lit Up' (one of my all-time favourite National
songs) on both nights which was an unexpected and brilliant bonus.</p>

<p>I’d been eagerly waiting for these dates to come around since I
<a href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/05/07/the-national-royal-albert-hall">saw</a>
the band on election night back in May at the Royal Albert Hall.</p>

<p>This beautiful photo taken by [Alison Philcock][] brilliantly captures
the mood and sense of expectation shortly before the band took the
stage.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/56632653@N06/5227979452/"
   title="IMG_1480 by Crystaltips74, on Flickr">
<img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4133/5227979452_c506d62e58.jpg"
width="500" height="375" alt="IMG_1480" /></a></p>

<p>My family were genuinely perplexed as to why a grown man was going to
see the same band play twice within three days and were unimpressed with
my reply of ‘Well, I couldn't get tickets for Tuesday'.</p>

<p>I also won a &pound;10 bet with Norma who bizarrely insisted that the band
would play the same set in precisely the same order. On Wednesday, two
of my favourite songs ‘All The Wine' and ‘About Today' replaced
‘Runaway' and ‘Little Faith'.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
