<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: xbox | Blog In Isolation]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/categories/xbox/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T20:07:32+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy C]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[three red rings of death]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2009/09/22/three-red-rings-of-death/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-22T09:54:26+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2009/09/22/three-red-rings-of-death</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Friday, Norman Junior III emerged from his bedroom, looked
mournfully at me and pronounced in a quiet voice: 'Dad - I've got the
three red rings of death.'</p>

<p>'Just have an aspirin and sit down quietly for a bit. Your mum will be
back soon.'</p>

<p>'No Dad - not me. It's my XBox. It has the dreaded <a href="http://support.microsoft.com/kb/907534">three red
rings</a> of death and won't boot.'</p>

<p>And so we embarked on a prolonged saga that involved a fruitless hunt
for a two year old receipt that revealed plenty of interesting long lost
items but not the actual receipt from Game.</p>

<p>Then I contacted Microsoft about the prospect of repairing a faulty
console that was out of warranty and had subsequently fallen by &pound;100 in
price.</p>

<p>Much to my surprise, Microsoft told me that, for this specific hardware
fault, the warranty had been extended to three years.</p>

<p>Microsoft checked the date of manufacture from the serial number,
confirmed the box was eligible for the extended warranty and asked me to
courier the faulty console, free of charge, back to their service centre
in Frankfurt, near Germany for repair.</p>

<p>Microsoft sent me the necessary paperwork to ship the XBox to Germany
using UPS. In turn, UPS sent me a package label, invoice, receipt and an
export certificate.</p>

<p>I then booked an appointment with UPS to collect the games console at my
convenience.</p>

<p>And all of this was accomplished without speaking to a single human
being - except for Norman Junior III who is doing well and making a fine
recovery after going 'Cold Turkey' from Call Of Duty.</p>

<p>It all sounds too good to be true...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
