<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: crm | Blog In Isolation]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/categories/crm/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T20:07:32+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy C]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CRM - Royal Mail style]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/01/02/crm-royal-mail-style/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-02T16:22:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/01/02/crm-royal-mail-style</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Before Christmas, my friendly postman tried to deliver a parcel when
no-one was home. Instead of leaving the parcel propped up by the front
door to be buried under the falling snow, inviting passers-by to steal
the potentially valuable item or slinging it into our dustbin, this
time he helpfully left a note asking me to collect the package from
the local sorting office or 'request a redelivery' on a subsequent
date using a form on the Royal Mail web site.</p>

<p>As I am quite lazy, I went for the latter option, and requested
redelivery for two days later. The Xmas parcel duly arrived on the
prescribed date so that was fine. Well done to the Royal Mail for
making the redelivery request option available online. Less work for
me. A little more work for them. Everyone's happy.</p>

<p>A full 10 days later, I was a little perplexed to receive the
following email from Royal Mail. At first, I assumed it was a feedback
request to 'Please rate our service' but no, it wasn't.</p>

<blockquote><p>Subject: Redelivery response</p>

<p>If you are now in receipt of your redelivered item, thank you for
using our on-line redelivery service and please delete this email.</p></blockquote>

<p>Ah OK so I can safely delete this email message as my parcel has been
successfully redelivered but let's read on just out of idle curiosity.</p>

<blockquote><p>Dear Sir or Madam</p>

<p>Thank you for requesting redelivery of your item.</p>

<p>Your local delivery office received your request and after searching
for your item was unable to locate it. This could be because you have
either already collected the item from the delivery office or it has
been redelivered.</p>

<p>If this is not the case may I firstly apologise for any
inconvenience you have been caused and for information on what to do
next please visit our website at www.royalmail.com or contact Customer
Services on 08457 740 740</p></blockquote>

<p>I had to read this correspondence three times before I was able to
parse the words - 'Your local delivery office received your request
and after searching for your item was unable to locate it'. Eh ? But
the local delivery office did receive my request and actioned it. The
redelivery request had a number associated with it so why didn't they
update the status with 'Redelivery scheduled for '19/12' ?</p>

<p>The next sentence is also rather odd - 'This could be because you have
either already collected the item from the delivery office or it has
been redelivered.' Somehow this implication of the first statement is
that this state of confusion may partially be my fault for having the
temerity to visit the local sorting office as requested to collect my
parcel. Again, it's clear the Royal Mail has no idea what actually
happened to this parcel. For all they know, it's sitting at the bottom
of my tall, black wheelie bin under two heavy sacks of Christmas
rubbish imminently destined for landfill.</p>

<p>However, even though the Royal Mail has no idea what happened to my
parcel, I can rest easy - 'If this is not the case may I firstly
apologise for any inconvenience you have been caused and for
information on what to do next, please visit our website or contact
Customer Services on 08457 740 740'.</p>

<p>So, if my parcel hadn't been successfully re-delivered or I hadn't
collected it in person, this email from Royal Mail Customer Services
hardly inspires confidence that they will inform me with any degree of
certainty what to do next.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CRM for bloggers]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/12/18/crm-bloggers/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-18T16:37:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/12/18/crm-bloggers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There's a common saying in Customer Relationship Management (CRM)
circles along the lines of:</p>

<blockquote><p>It takes 10,000 times more time/money/effort to acquire a new customer
than it takes to retain an existing customer.</p></blockquote>

<p>Evidence of this is commonplace; introductory offers, improved interest
rates, free Parker pen and pencil gift set and enticements for new
customers for which existing customers are ineligible.</p>

<p>Now I occasionally claim that I am writing this blog purely for me,
myself and I. What I mean by that is that I tend to write what I want
when I want and don't feel pressured to produce content on a regular
ongoing basis. However, that's not entirely true; if it was I could
equally well write this stream of consciousness into a A5 notebook
locked in my top drawer where no-one would ever see it.</p>

<p>Let's be honest - people are blogging to get noticed and everyone
likes feedback (even if it's negative feedback) and it's fantastic if,
just occasionally, someone says 'God - that post about LinkedIn and
pole dancing made me laugh'.</p>

<p>A recent
<a href="http://nbrightside.com/blog/2006/06/21/the-curious-case-of-the-missing-about-page#comment-113403409">comment</a>
by Bill (which I will reproduce here) rather took me by surprise and
made me pause for thought</p>

<blockquote><p>I like your blog, but just one thing about it frustrates me - you
“tag” posts, but I can't seem to find an index of these tags. (?) For
example, I like to read your comments on emacs - but without such an
index, I am forced to use Google to search your site.</p></blockquote>

<p>Now here was a potential customer (an interested like-minded reader or
even hopefully, that rare animal, a brand new subscriber) for my
business (my humble blog) and what was I doing to welcome him, to
encourage him, to help him find his way around my blog ? Nothing.
Absolutely nothing.</p>

<p>After giving this some thought, I decided to take prompt and decisive
action:</p>

<blockquote><p>Many thanks for popping by and bothering to leave some constructive
criticism about the lack of decent navigation options on this blog.
There's a couple of reasons for this:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>I recently moved this blog to Drupal 7 and I didn't actually know
how to add tag clouds, archive pages, previous/next post, related
posts or search functionality.</p></li>
<li><p>In the past, I have played with all of the above on both WordPress
and Habari in an effort to keep casual readers lingering for
longer and my gut feeling was that none of these additions made a
blind bit of difference to Pages/Visit and merely cluttered up the
blog.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>However, prompted by your comment, I have now added 'Tags' together
with a search box on the sidebar and an 'Archives' tab allowing you to
browse by year or month.</p></blockquote>

<p>Unfortunately, I never heard from the mysterious Bill ever again. A
cautionary tale and a valuable lesson in CRM for all small-time
bloggers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comet 0 Customer 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/12/06/comet-0-customer-3/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-06T14:53:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/12/06/comet-0-customer-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the weekend, I purchased a new printer after replacing the ink
cartridges failed to reinstate the ability to print in black on my Canon
IP4000.</p>

<p>Previously, I'd researched which printers had decent Linux support and
decided on an <a href="http://h10010.www1.hp.com/wwpc/uk/en/ho/WF05a/18972-18972-238444-410635-410635-4066450.html?lang=en&amp;jumpid=oc_R1002_UKENC-001_HP%20Deskjet%203050%20All-in-One%20Printer%20-%20J610a&amp;cc=uk">HP Deskjet 3050</a>. This is a wireless printer so I hoped
that the Windows PC's in the house would be able to print directly and
the management of the printer (inkjet levels) would be easier. My
current Canon IP4000 has served me well but is pretty old and I was
surprised to find I could pick up an HP wireless printer for &pound;34.</p>

<p>I checked the price on Amazon to find the price has risen to &pound;38.99 in
the intervening two weeks - not just at Amazon but at all online
retailers I normally use. No problem - still excellent value. As Norma
is patiently waiting to submit a couple of essays for her course, I
decided to venture out to try to buy a printer as delivery times from
Amazon could be delayed given the recent cold spell.</p>

<p>I walked into Comet - the HP Deskjet 3050 was on the shelf listed at
the price I'd originally seen - &pound;34.00. I darted next door to a
cavernous PC World which is the size of a aircraft hanger and a gadget
heaven. They also had the printer but now at the higher price of
&pound;38.99.</p>

<p>I went back to Comet, picked up the last remaining Deskjet box and
walked up to the till. The girl swiped the barcode and said (much as I
expected) - 'That will be &pound;38.99, Sir'. 'Oh I think that's a
mistake - it's listed as &pound;34.00 on the display'. 'No, sorry,
Sir. It's coming up on the computer as &pound;38.99'. 'Sorry but the
price on the display is &pound;34.00 and you have to charge me that
price for the printer. It’s the law'.</p>

<p>She interrupted me ‘Well I will have to see this for myself. Can you
show me ?' So we both ambled over to the display area of various
printers. The shop assistant wasn't best pleased and she muttered ‘Are
you absolutely sure it's the same printer, the same make and model ?'</p>

<p>We arrived at the display item for the HP DeskJet 3050 printer where the
price was displayed as clear as day, in black and white as &pound;34.00. She
turned back towards the till without a word so I duly followed, feeling
slightly guilty.</p>

<p>'Right then, Sir'. And she entered a manual override for the price and
entered &pound;34.99. That will be ‘&pound;34.99 please'. ‘But the
price is &pound;34 dead, &pound;34 exactly'. 'Was it ?' By now my
patience and my good humour at finding the desired printer in stock
and saving &pound;5 was being tempered by this girl's surly and
unhelpful attitude.</p>

<p>‘Listen. We've just walked over to check the price. We did that because
I know what the price is but you don't. Didn't you even look at the
price ? What was the point of going over if you're can't be bothered
looking at the price?'</p>

<p>‘So you're really going to argue with me over 99p are you ? I've already
keyed it now.'</p>

<p>'Yes - because the price is &pound;34.' She emitted a long sigh under her
breath and she entered the correct price and I proferred my credit card.</p>

<p>And now in a voice scarily reminiscent of Catherine Tate as the TGI
waitress; ‘Would you be wanting extended insurance cover with that, at
all, Sir ?'. 'Oh no - thanks - just the printer, thanks.' 'Insurance
cover is available for just &pound;24.99 for 3 years and &pound;34.99
for a full, comprehensive 5 years peace of mind'.</p>

<p>'I’m not really likely to insure something that cost me &pound;34 for
&pound;35. If it blows up after 1 year and 1 day, I’d just buy another
printer that is likely to be better, faster and probably cheaper.'</p>

<p>‘Well that's entirely up to you, Sir but these printers can be quite
unreliable.'</p>

<p>'No really. Just the printer thanks'. 'Right - so that’ll be &pound;34.00 for
the printer then.'</p>

<p>I went to nudge the printer box towards me in a precursor to leaving
this godforsaken store and erasing this girl's morose, stupid, miserable
face from my memory bank. For ever.</p>

<p>‘Can I interest you in more ink cartridges, Sir ? Special offer in
December on all inkjets - buy one set of ink and get another one at half
price.'</p>

<p>‘No thanks. I normally get my cartridges off the Internet.'</p>

<p>‘OK, Sir. That's entirely up to you but I must tell you that printers
only come with a 'starter pack' which only print 50 pages or so so you
might run out very quickly.'</p>

<p>I smelled bullshit here but I wouldn't put it past the printer
companies in an effort to recoup their loss on the actual device to
ship with smaller, low capacity cartridges. Worse, the spectre of
Norma printing out several lengthy papers and articles and the ink
running out just as she printed of the final revision of her essay for
submission was hovering overhead like a hungry vulture.</p>

<p>'No thanks. No insurance. No additional ink. Just the printer. Thanks.'</p>

<p>I got home, quickly installed and configured the printer and
discovered HP provide two standard cartridges (black and the 3 colour
mix). No starter pack.</p>

<p>I quickly checked wireless printing from three Windows computers (XP,
Vista and Windows 7) and downloaded the latest version HP native Linux
software
(<a href='http://hplipopensource.com/hplip-web/index.html'>HPLIP</a>)
to configure and manage the printer which was conveniently available
in the Fedora 14 repositories.</p>

<p>Finally, I ordered two spare cartridges from Amazon for &pound;20
compared to &pound;24 at Comet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[three red rings of death]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2009/09/22/three-red-rings-of-death/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-22T09:54:26+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2009/09/22/three-red-rings-of-death</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Friday, Norman Junior III emerged from his bedroom, looked
mournfully at me and pronounced in a quiet voice: 'Dad - I've got the
three red rings of death.'</p>

<p>'Just have an aspirin and sit down quietly for a bit. Your mum will be
back soon.'</p>

<p>'No Dad - not me. It's my XBox. It has the dreaded <a href="http://support.microsoft.com/kb/907534">three red
rings</a> of death and won't boot.'</p>

<p>And so we embarked on a prolonged saga that involved a fruitless hunt
for a two year old receipt that revealed plenty of interesting long lost
items but not the actual receipt from Game.</p>

<p>Then I contacted Microsoft about the prospect of repairing a faulty
console that was out of warranty and had subsequently fallen by &pound;100 in
price.</p>

<p>Much to my surprise, Microsoft told me that, for this specific hardware
fault, the warranty had been extended to three years.</p>

<p>Microsoft checked the date of manufacture from the serial number,
confirmed the box was eligible for the extended warranty and asked me to
courier the faulty console, free of charge, back to their service centre
in Frankfurt, near Germany for repair.</p>

<p>Microsoft sent me the necessary paperwork to ship the XBox to Germany
using UPS. In turn, UPS sent me a package label, invoice, receipt and an
export certificate.</p>

<p>I then booked an appointment with UPS to collect the games console at my
convenience.</p>

<p>And all of this was accomplished without speaking to a single human
being - except for Norman Junior III who is doing well and making a fine
recovery after going 'Cold Turkey' from Call Of Duty.</p>

<p>It all sounds too good to be true...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[credit where credit is due]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/11/15/credit-where-credit-is-due/"/>
    <updated>2005-11-15T05:54:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/11/15/credit-where-credit-is-due</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In an earlier
<a href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/10/29/beware-of-shopping-at-dell-computers/">post</a>,
I moaned about Dell's opaque pricing model on their UK Web site.
However, people (especially me) are very quick to moan and complain
but often slow to give thanks and appreciation.</p>

<p>I subsequently contacted Dell Customer Services to complain that the
invoice was for a different amount agreed on the phone (strong case)
and the fact I discovered that I could configure an identical PC for
an even lower price (weaker argument).</p>

<p>The lady from Dell Customer Services initially suggested that I cancel
the original order and simply place another order online at the lower
price. I pointed out that this was a little silly as it would mean
cancelling an order for one computer and adding a new order for a
brand new computer with the identical specification.</p>

<p>In any event, it transpired that the PC had already been dispatched
from Dell to the courier company, so I would have to call a different
department 'Pre Sales Delivery' to cancel the order.</p>

<p>The gentleman in 'Pre Sales Delivery' was more helpful and agreed that
cancelling the current order was ludicrous. He offered me a
All-In-One-Printer free of charge. While this was a nice gesture, I
told him I already had a printer. He then offered me a digital camera
free of charge but I already had one of those too. I stood my ground
and insisted on the refund and he finally agreed.</p>

<p>The gentleman also gave me his direct email and the name of his
supervisor in case of any subsequent issues with the refund. So, I am
pleased to say that Dell honoured the lowest price for the PC. It was
inconvenient, took a little persistence and a few phone calls but for
54GBP it was well worth it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
