<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: humour | Blog In Isolation]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/categories/humour/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T20:07:32+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy C]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[humour on BBC breakfast]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/07/21/humour-bbc-breakfast/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-21T09:23:58+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/07/21/humour-bbc-breakfast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>BBC Breakfast ran a story this morning about the sale of
<a href="http://www.woodlands.co.uk/buying-a-wood/">woodlands</a>. The gentlemen
responsible for selling woodlands was quite a comedian. He started his
act with:</p>

<blockquote><p>'In these difficult economic times, people are looking to invest in
woodlands to hedge their bets...'</p></blockquote>

<p>and then, referring to the potential investment opportunity and
without a glimmer of a smile, he delivered the immaculate line</p>

<blockquote><p>'In a few years time, once the wood has matured, people will see
that you can get income from trees'.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[farewell Paul Scholes]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/05/31/farewell-paul-scholes/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-31T09:11:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/05/31/farewell-paul-scholes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/RD2bDI-AOBjwHYPgXVHS1w?feat=embedwebsite"><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-queZ1d_BoUs/TeSv7gEeUII/AAAAAAAABvE/7vhA7va4eyA/s800/Paul-Scholes-Manchester-United-Barcelona-Cham_2602915.jpg"
height="298" width="218"></a></p>

<p>One of my favourite United players - for his sublime skills on the
pitch and the modest, understated way he conducted himself off
it. Thanks for all the memories, Paul.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[why I hate Kitties and Whips]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/11/13/why-i-hate-kitties-and-whips/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-13T10:46:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/11/13/why-i-hate-kitties-and-whips</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was recently in a pub when a lady looked expectantly at me and said
‘Fancy a whip for this ?' I looked a little taken aback and hesitated
until she helpfully clarified ‘A kitty. For the drinks. Shall we have a
whip round and I'll then buy some drinks'. In a very polite British way,
I proffered a ten pound note and said ‘Oh that will be great. Thanks for
sorting that out. A pint of London Pride for me, please'.</p>

<p>Whereas what I really wanted to say was. ‘We are two couples having a
quick Saturday night drink after watching some amateur dramatics
featuring some friends. It's five past ten so we'll probably have two
drinks. Why on earth should we contribute to a kitty ? You buy us a
drink and I promise that we will reciprocate.'</p>

<p>There are many different problems with these whiprounds and kitties:</p>

<ul>
<li>Someone has to manage the money.</li>
<li>Someone, normally the fastest drinker, always ends up thirsty as,
like a training course, the pace is governed by the speed of the
slowest person present. If girls are involved, you can actually die
of thirst and lose your kitty contribution.</li>
<li>People always think things are cheaper than they actually are so are
sceptical when the demand comes round to top up the kitty.</li>
<li>As the night progresses, people become less inhibited and contribute
massive amounts ‘Here's &pound;50. That should sort it for a while.'</li>
<li>At the end, the kitty has to be sub-divided and the proceeds
returned to all contributors. This is a variant on the ‘splitting
the bill' syndrome at a restaurant - only more complicated and time
consuming. Forget the last train home. You've missed it. You're
getting an expensive taxi. Still, at least the drinks were equitably
divided.</li>
<li>I once had the misfortune to be appointed ‘Kitty Treasurer'. This
was a complete nightmare because people expect you to continually go
to the bar. Time after time because ‘you've got the whip'. I never
spoke to anyone but the bar staff all night.</li>
</ul>


<p>So please don't invite me into your ‘kitty' or contribute to your stupid
‘whip'. This is the correct and proper way to ensure a night of trouble
free, enjoyable drinking:</p>

<ul>
<li>Get in a round with mates who drink at vaguely your rate. With
blokes this doesn't matter as slowcoaches simply accrue 5 full,
untouched pints while the rounds continue to be brought over to the
table regardless.</li>
<li>Ensure the rounds are ‘equalised' by the end of the night. This
means that everyone in the round buys the same number of pints. I
can't emphasis the importance of this enough.</li>
<li>Choose the size of the round appropriately. If you're in a group of
4, you need to prepare to sup 4,8, 12 or even 16 pints.</li>
<li>Large groups can lead to livers the size and colour of George
Best's. Consider splitting large groups into 3's or 4's.</li>
<li>Don't skew the financial calculations by having a crafty ‘Southern
Comfort' on the penultimate round because ‘I'm a little full of
beer'. Just drink pints. You're a man. That's why you're in a pub
not a wine bar.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[drowning man]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/09/08/drowning-man/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-08T10:24:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/09/08/drowning-man</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Brightside family holiday in Spain was a very relaxing affair. For a
period of 10 days, I didn't watch a television, read a newspaper, stare
at a computer screen or even turn my mobile phone on.</p>

<p>In fact, I sat by the pool, listened to music, swam, ate fantastic
seafood, thought a lot and ploughed my way through the Millennium
trilogy by Stieg Larsson.</p>

<p><a href="http://picasaweb.google.co.uk/lh/photo/fYXZfK5ABbL1eHCIngPp2g?feat=embedwebsite"><img src="http://lh3.ggpht.com/_l2uGy1RGCiE/TIdiF80AvLI/AAAAAAAABn0/b4PtHcYd1Y0/s400/DSC00370.JPG" /></a></p>

<p>One hot, sunny afternoon, my relaxation was disturbed by the most
awful, horrible, blood curdling screams. I consulted my iTouch; 'D-7'
by that popular 90's beat combo - Nirvana. Ah that explains it. I
returned to 'The Girl Who Played With Fire' and the exciting
adventures of Lisbeth Salander.</p>

<p>Almost immediately, my train of thought was interrupted by yet more
loud, agonising, terrifying animalistic screams. I looked across at
Norma who was embracing the Spanish culture with a short mid-afternoon
siesta so it definitely wasn't her.</p>

<p>I consulted the iTouch again as the blood curdling screaming continued
unabated. Ah - 'Welcome to the Atrocity Exhibition' by the popular
80's beat combo - Joy Division from the 'Live at the Paradiso' bootleg
(available from all good Torrent sites).</p>

<p>I reduced the volume by a notch and was about to summon up the energy to
adjust the parasol to get some shade.</p>

<p>Suddenly, away to my right, I saw a flash of green as my radiant wife,
Norma, suddenly and spontaneously leapt from her sun-lounger. That's
strange I thought - Cocktail Happy Hour doesn't start for another 40
minutes. I watched Norma as she ran at breakneck speed towards the
swimming pool.</p>

<p>I thought I'd be sociable so I turned my music off and went to join her
for some watery frolics followed by discussion of the very important
issue of the choice of venue for tonight's meal.</p>

<p>I stood next to her at the edge of the swimming pool and suddenly my
brain went into overdrive. My iTouch was off and yet the loud, agonising
screams continued.</p>

<p>Wait - there was a middle aged man splashing about in the water. Wait -
is he in difficulty ? Wait - he can't be - this pool is 1.80m at its
deepest. I can stand up in the pool everywhere apart from 2 square
metres where I have to stand on tip-toes. Wait - he's shorter than me.
Wait - what the heck is going on here ?</p>

<p>As my brain struggled to parse the situation in front of me, Norma
spontaneously and spectacularly leapt into the swimming pool.</p>

<p>It's a horrible, hackneyed cliche but it was like watching life in
slow motion. The middle aged man was still thrashing about rather
frantically and he was making the most horrible noises. Loud,
prolonged, deep blood curdling noises. At first, I wondered if he was
a Joy Division or Nirvana fan and just singing 'D-7' followed by
'Welcome to the Atrocity Exhibition' in his very own unique version of
underwater, punk karaoke.</p>

<p>Norma and another gentleman in the pool gradually moved towards drowning
man like two sharks closing in on their prey. But without the triangular
fins.</p>

<p>Finally, my brain woke up. This guy didn't appear to be larking about.
There were no children with him. He genuinely looked like he was
flailing his arms around and panicking like, well, a drowning man. His
eyes were open and he was conscious and vertical but I wondered if he
was having a fit or an asthma or panic attack.</p>

<p>As I considered entering the water, Norma got closer to the drowning
man. I heard a voice behind me: 'Can we go and get an ice-cream yet
Dad ? It's nearly 4 o'clock.'</p>

<p>My daughter Norma Jeane was at my side carefully reviewing progress on
her sun tan and, incredibly was thinking about her stomach rather than
the drama unfolding in front of us. Even more incredibly, Norma Jeane is
a qualified life guard.</p>

<p>'Hang on Norma Jeane - your Mum's a little busy at the moment saving a
drowning man.'</p>

<p>'Oh - shall I just get her a Magnum Classic then ? Have you got any
Euros ?'</p>

<p>Norma reached the flailing man and went to lift him. The man seized
his opportunity and pushed down hard on Norma's shoulder to lift
himself out of the water and get some air into his lungs The laws of
physics meant that he immediately pushed Norma fully under the
water. Norman Jeane offered 'Oh yeah - that's a classic life saving
mistake. We did it on the course. You should always support the
drowning man low down before he has a chance to grab you and risk
drowning you.'</p>

<p>Thankfully, the man's screams finally subsided and Norma and the other
man lifted the man, rather ungracefully, up onto the poolside - laid
out like a beached seal. The hotel pool man immaculately clad in white
shirt and white long trousers (like an extra from 'An Officer and a
Gentleman') ambled over. 'Everything ees OK, si ?'</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sherlock Burns and Dr. Hall investigate]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/09/07/sherlock-burns-and-dr-hall-investigate/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-07T09:43:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/09/07/sherlock-burns-and-dr-hall-investigate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>[<img src="http://lh5.ggpht.com/_l2uGy1RGCiE/TIYHrMP2-SI/AAAAAAAABng/zNKL6tOY-Wc/s400/sherlock-holmes.jpg" alt="image" />][]</p>

<p>‘Burns - I guess this means I can book the hotel for four nights and
cancel the flights to OpenWorld then ?'</p>

<p>It was 10:30 am on a dull, grey overcast Monday morning in Manchester.
Sherlock Burns and Doctor Timothy Hall had just emerged from a
fractious, tense kick-off meeting at Tiger Telecom. Sherlock Burns and
Dr. Timothy Hall had been called by the IT director at short notice to
investigate a sudden and marked degradation in the performance of the
production database</p>

<p>‘No. On the contrary, Doctor Hall. Please ensure the Hackney carriage is
booked for 4pm together with two first class tickets for the return
train journey to Euston. I have every confidence this case will be
solved by lunchtime. This time tomorrow we will be on a plane to
California.'</p>

<p>‘But Burns - we just sat through a 90 minute meeting with no obvious
solution. Why, I do declare, the customer can't even articulate the
problem clearly and all the project team are arguing with each other.
How on earth -'</p>

<p>‘Dr. Hall - do you recall the pretty chart showing the 'Key Business
Transaction Response Times' ? What did you observe ?'</p>

<p>‘Err - I believe it was Excel 2007 and used a fancy pivot table…'</p>

<p>‘No, no - not that. Didn't you look closely at the X-axis ? The timeline
of the monitoring process was every 10 minutes. After August 15th, the
granularity of the dots changed to every 10 seconds. This coincided with
the performance problems and undoubtedly means the frequency of the
monitoring probe was modified resulting in the increased load on the
system.'</p>

<p>‘Oh Burns - that truly is absolutely magnificent. How did you spot that
?'</p>

<p>‘Obvious Dr. Hall, blindingly obvious. I suspect you will find someone,
somewhere has got his asterisks mixed up when he editted the crontab. A
common failing when you try to convert Windows support staff to the
superior Unix platform. Now as we were brought through the office by our
host and walked through the call centre area, what did you notice ?'</p>

<p>‘Well Burns - I noticed a lot of pretty girls wearing headsets. That
blonde, in particular, was stunning -'</p>

<p>‘No, no - I'm talking about the plethora of 'New Hire Induction Guide'
on their desks. Tiger Telecom has obviously hired all these people
recently which is also contributing more load to the system.'</p>

<p>‘No - Burns - that can't be right. You specifcally asked them in the
meeting what had changed recently and they all insisted: 'Nothing.
Absolutely nothing.'</p>

<p>‘That's why we are here, Dr Hall. Unless you saw it with your own eyes
it didn't happen. Another factor at play here is the Senior Oracle DBA.
He is incompetent and must be replaced immediately.'</p>

<p>‘Oh Burns - how can you say that ? He seemed like a lovely bloke to me
and don't forget he bought us our Latte's.'</p>

<p>‘Shut up Hall. What did you notice on his desk ?'</p>

<p>‘On his desk ? Well nothing apart from that rather amusing 'You don't
have to be mad to work here but it helps' postcard and a photo of his
wife sunbathing in Crete….'</p>

<p>‘No, no. I'm talking about the technical books on his desk. He had a
pile of Oracle books - all the usual suspects; Kyte, Lewis, Milsap and
Antognini. But on the very top of that pile was a curious tome - 'Oracle
Tuning - The Definitive Reference Second Edition' by Donald Burleson. No
self respecting Oracle DBA would have that combination of books. That
alerted me that something was amiss.'</p>

<p>‘Oh come off it, Burns. I think you're putting 2 and 2 together and
making 5 here. That's very unfair -'</p>

<p>‘Dr. Hall. I opened the Burleson book up and noted the following
inscription on the inside cover: 'Barry - all the best in the future and
may your redo logs always be multiplexed :-)' Therefore I conclude this
gentleman was dismissed from his previous post as a contract DBA
following an unfortunate, and ultimately fruitless, exercise in media
recovery. On a production system for an investment bank.'</p>

<p>‘Ah OK, I see, Burns. While we're discussing the technical staff, I just
wanted to mention that PL/SQL developer. I think he needs to be sacked
too.'</p>

<p>‘Interesting, Dr. Hall. Why do you hold that opinion ?'</p>

<p>‘Well - when you asked him how much source code, how many lines of
PL/SQL, how many packages he'd written, he couldn't produce anything.
Nothing. And to think he calls himself a 'PL/SQL developer. He's
obviously an imposter.'</p>

<p>Burns smiled inwardly.</p>

<p>'Not so fast, young, keen, impetuous Doctor Hall. While what you say is
true, the young man did proffer a explanation for this. He showed me a
source code repository populated with comprehensive, well written and
tuned SQL scripts. Why - I do declare he even used Analytic functions.
Young Mr. Barnstormworth justified his stance thus: “If it can't be done
in a single SQL statement, use PL/SQL. If it can't be done in PL/SQL,
use a Java Stored procedure. Otherwise consider ‘C'.”</p>

<p>Dr. Hall looked amazed as Burns had solved another mystery and he hadn't
even had to chat with the Head of IT Operations.</p>

<p>‘Now my good man. That's more than enough work for one morning. I am
ready to eat now and rather appropriately, I think I spotted a 'Pret A
Manager' adjacent to the offices where we can discuss my forthcoming
‘State of the Nation' keynote presentation at Oracle OpenWorld.</p>

<p>The ‘Council Of War' was duly reassembled at 3pm and Sherlock Burns took
a long drag on his pipe before addressing the group:</p>

<ul>
<li>‘Fix the monitor probe interval.'</li>
<li>‘Sack the Oracle DBA.'</li>
<li>‘Promote Daniel Barnstomworth to 'Senior VP of Database
Engineering'.</li>
<li>‘Deploy another RAC node by the end of the year to cater for the
increased user base.'</li>
<li>‘Here's my invoice. Good Bye'.</li>
</ul>


<p>  [<img src="http://lh5.ggpht.com/_l2uGy1RGCiE/TIYHrMP2-SI/AAAAAAAABng/zNKL6tOY-Wc/s400/sherlock-holmes.jpg" alt="image" />]: http://picasaweb.google.co.uk/lh/photo/WJDWHophTNIdwzEJ6Je7hQ?feat=embedwebsite</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
