<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: emacs | Blog In Isolation]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/categories/emacs/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T20:07:32+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy C]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[the joy of Markdown]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/05/17/joy-markdown/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-17T22:27:58+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/05/17/joy-markdown</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For many years, I have flitted between a plethora of different
blogging platforms mainly out of curiosity, boredom, frustration or
occasionally sheer bloody mindedness.</p>

<p>I have lost draft posts in WordPress, Tumblr, Posterous and Habari due
to network glitches, browser crashes, my own stupidity and a broken
AutoSave plugin.</p>

<p>One night in a lonely hotel room, the realisation suddenly dawned on
me that my frustration with all of these blogging platforms was that I
spent a lot of time in the post editor and none of the post editors
did what I wanted.</p>

<p>Whether you use Tumblr, Posterous, WordPress, Habari, Drupal, Movable
Type, Django-Mingus or another esoteric blog platform, you normally
find yourself composing content in a Web browser within a blank text
box writing raw HTML.</p>

<p>Alternatively, you might be using some WYSIWYG editor that helps you
insert the appropriate HTML tags.</p>

<p>There are a few things wrong with this scenario as far as I'm
concerned:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>I don't particularly want or need to learn and remember HTML
tags. People ask why there's a HTML reference card in the lavatory.</p></li>
<li><p>WYSIWYG editors can produce monstrous, bloated, ugly and sometimes,
as a bonus, invalid HTML.</p></li>
<li><p>I don't really want to use a WYSIWYG editor. I have invested time
learning to scratch the surface of the functionality provided by the
one true editor - Emacs.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>After reading, but steadfastly ignoring multiple articles about
<a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax">Markdown</a> for
many months and making a mental note to investigate further, I finally
set aside 10 minutes to do so.</p>

<p>Without being over dramatic, Markdown has changed my life. For the
better.</p>

<p>Markdown is a markup language ('geddit ?') that uses a easy to read
notation as shorthand for HTML.</p>

<p>The beauty of the Markdown syntax is that text written in the Markdown
format is perfectly readable. This makes reading, scanning, reviewing
and editing text much easier and quicker.</p>

<p>I'm a simple man with simple tastes so my blog posts primarily use
paragraphs, lists, hyperlinks and the very occasional image.</p>

<p>A hyperlink in Markdown looks like</p>

<pre><code>[Markdown](http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax)
</code></pre>

<p>A blank line indicates the end of a paragraph. Again, this is how we
compose text in emails and is so much more natural than</p>

<pre><code>&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>The HTML tags above are a preformatted block. In Markdown, this is
simply denoted by a 4 character indent.</p>

<p>To <em>emphasise</em> a word, you simply enclose the word in asterisk
characters which is what a lot of luddite, bearded Unix geeks tend to
do anyway. Using two asterisk characters will result in <strong>bold</strong> text.</p>

<p>Similarly, if you want to force a line break you simply append two
blank spaces to the end of a line.</p>

<p>Code blocks are introduced by a single quote.</p>

<p><code>   printf("Hello World\n");</code></p>

<p>Bulleted lists are introduced by a hypen or asterisk character so a
list of my favourite fruits would be written as:</p>

<pre><code>* Apples
* Oranges
* Pears
* Bananas
</code></pre>

<p>Ordered lists use numbers and look like, well, ordered lists.</p>

<pre><code>1. Giggs
2. Scholes
3. Cantona
</code></pre>

<p>Quotes are also easy and intuitive introduced by the '>' character.</p>

<blockquote><p>Are you still doing what you did 5 years ago ?<br/>
Yeah ? Well don't make a career out of it.<br/>
Mark E. Smith (The Fall)</p></blockquote>

<p>Most blogging platforms either provides native Markdown support or has
plugins available to provide such functionality.</p>

<p>However, the real beauty of Markdown for me is that Emacs inevitably
has a powerful Markdown mode that provides font colouring, additional
menu shortcuts for the common constructs and a feature to examine the
generated HTML in an Emacs buffer or preview the results in a Web
browser.</p>

<p><a
href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/sykhGbfuwfI5NUo4vc_yTg?feat=embedwebsite"><img
src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_l2uGy1RGCiE/TdLzq1bo1dI/AAAAAAAABuk/ibt1UdW_VpY/s640/Markdown-Emacs.png"
height="640" width="614" /></a></p>

<p>This is incredibly useful for me as I can quickly check the generated HTML and even validate my blog posts. Validating my posts wasn't easy before as the addition of the Disqus Javascript code generates a number of warnings from the W3C validator.</p>

<p><a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/grEBQVK_F7elXpEFtyQNEQ?feat=embedwebsite"><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_l2uGy1RGCiE/TdLz1_fNSxI/AAAAAAAABus/LksKcNKG7_Q/s640/Markdown-Preview.png" height="388" width="640" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
