<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: google | Blog In Isolation]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/categories/google/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T20:07:32+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy C]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Music - available by 2017]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/07/26/google-music-available-2017/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-26T11:07:05+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/07/26/google-music-available-2017</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks ago, I signed up for a invitation to Google Music. The
service is only available in the US but, by a lucky chance of fate, I
just happened to be connected to my corporate VPN so I was successful
and an invitation duly arrived in my Inbox.</p>

<p>Initially, the Google Music Manager software didn't support Linux. Nor
was the Ogg Vorbis audio format supported so I didn't pursue it any
further as both of these were show stoppers for me. I don't intend
re-ripping my entire music collection to MP3 format.</p>

<p>However, last week, Google released a Linux version of Music Manager
and added
'<a href="http://www.google.com/support/music/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;answer=1100462&amp;topic=1100183">support</a>'
for Ogg format audio files. The 'support' for the Ogg format is
slightly strange - Ogg audio files will be transcoded back to 320kps
MP3 files which represents a conversion from one lossy format to
another lossy format. Hopefully, in the longer term, there will be
true native support for Ogg.</p>

<p>Anyway, I downloaded the Music Manager software and started uploading
my music collection mainly so I could listen to music on my netbook
which currently runs <a href="http://chromeos.hexxeh.net/">Chromium OS</a>.</p>

<p>I started the upload 2 days ago and it's been running during the
day. So far, it has managed to upload 505 songs out of a total 1,880
so it's not exactly a speedy process.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[first and last and always - Google Reader]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/01/05/first-and-last-and-always-google-reader/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-05T15:21:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2011/01/05/first-and-last-and-always-google-reader</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Steve Rubel has
<a href="http://www.steverubel.com/a-return-to-feed-reading-tops-my-2011-tech-re">resolved</a>
to return to feed reading in 2011.</p>

<p>However, I have been using Google Reader since 2007 and use it daily
to catch up with the tech and sports news in addition to my favourite
blogs. I honestly can't imagine life without it. I was also interested
by a recent
<a href="http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/google-reader-bookmarking-service/">article</a>
(prompted by the demise of delicio.us) that described the use of
Google Reader as a bookmarking service.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[the looming spectre of Google]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2007/05/25/the-looming-spectre-of-google/"/>
    <updated>2007-05-25T07:47:15+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2007/05/25/the-looming-spectre-of-google</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The recent
<a href="http://scobleizer.com/2007/05/23/dog-distrustdisdain-of-google-moves-in/">storm</a>
in the
<a href="http://www.therssweblog.com/?guid=20070524110855">anti-blogosphere</a>
about <a href="http://www.google.com/">Google</a>
<a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2007/05/23/100-million-payday-for-feedburner-this-deal-is-confirmed/">acquiring</a>
<a href="http://www.feedburner.com">Feedburner</a>, the frightening
<a href="http://www.geeknewscentral.com/archives/007047.html">prospect</a> of
Google placing ads in your precious feeds, capturing all your personal
data, monitoring your every movement (online and offline) and logging
your brainwaves into the Google data warehouse is starting to irritate
me.</p>

<p>Despite the corporate
<a href="http://investor.google.com/conduct.html">motto</a>, please remember
Google is evil and 2084 is just around the corner, folks. Be aware
that Google just announced a partnership with global law enforcement
agencies to upload all CCT footage to YouTube.</p>

<p>Thankfully, some
<a href="http://marshallk.com/why-buying-feedburner-is-really-smart-of-google">intelligent</a>
<a href="http://andybeard.eu/2007/05/77-reasons-why-google-buying-feedburner-is-a-match-made-in-heaven-hell.html">people</a>
are able to distance themselves from the hype and present a more
<a href="http://scobleizer.com/2007/05/24/another-reason-i-use-google-reader/">balanced</a>
viewpoint.</p>

<p>Another irritant is idiots bleating, ironically enough, in Google
Groups about the lack of
<a href="http://groups.google.com/group/analytics-help-basics/browse_frm/thread/648a3ded5712a1e7/2f37bba1b8a3346c?lnk=gst&amp;q=monthly&amp;rnum=2#2f37bba1b8a3346c">monthly</a>
reports in the revamped Analytics and
<a href="http://groups.google.com/group/Google-Labs-Reader/browse_frm/thread/46ecef4ffd2722da">deficiencies</a>
in Reader.</p>

<p>If you don't like Analytics V2, go back to <a href="http://sitemeter.sitetoolbox.com/">Site
Meter</a> to track your e-commerce
site.  Let me know how you get on.</p>

<p>If you can't stand <a href="http://www.google.com/reader/view/">Reader</a>, shut
up and go back to
<a href="http://www.vecosys.com/2007/05/24/i-hate-the-bloglines-plumber/">Bloglines</a>
and moan about that instead.</p>

<p>If you can no longer tolerate the unreliability and limitations of
Docs and Spreadsheets, upgrade to Office 2007 and use Word and
<a href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2006/09/14/google-versus-microsoft/">Excel</a>.
The choice is yours.</p>

<p>I
<a href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2007/02/19/am-i-a-google-whore-yet/">use</a>
a lot of Google products (Gmail, Reader, Calendar, Analytics,
Notebook,
<a href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2007/03/07/in-praise-of-google-desktop/">Desktop</a>,
Bookmarks, IG,
<a href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2006/10/11/google-docs-and-spreadsheets/">Docs</a>,
Groups, Webmaster, Adsense oh and, err that Search thingy). My view is
that all are excellent, innovative software products and, best of all,
completely free of charge.</p>

<p>I really don't care that Google has stored every single keyword
related to my searches from October 1991.</p>

<p>I honestly don't care that Google has copies of my homework
<a href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2006/06/05/novel-homework-excuse/">excuses</a>
and letters to the Inland Revenue. Believe me, the contents are really
not that earth shattering.</p>

<p>I truly don't care that Google has copies of every single email I have
ever sent and received because, surprisingly, I have nothing to
hide. I only wish Google could get behind corporate firewalls and
retrieve the remainder as I have lost some magnificent blogging
material over the years.</p>

<p>If you are genuinely worried that Google is going to tell you what to
'<a href="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/c3e49548-088e-11dc-b11e-000b5df10621.html">eat for
tea</a>',
maybe you should do the world a favour and start a protest on behalf
of all Interweb users by going on an indefinite hunger
strike. Immediately.</p>

<p>If you are a child molester or jumped the
<a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/sport1/hi/football/teams/l/liverpool/6686867.stm">turnstiles</a>
last night in Athens, then, by all means, please disable all cookies,
use <a href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2007/05/11/dont-ask/">Ask.com</a> or
give your computer to charity.</p>

<p>As for me, I am putting my money where my mouth in. The next purchase
in my
<a href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/11/21/my-personal-pensions-crisis/">SIPP</a>
will be the purchase of &pound;7,000 of
<a href="http://finance.google.com/finance?q=goog">GOOG</a> stock. Tomorrow.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Reader]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/10/10/google-reader/"/>
    <updated>2005-10-10T20:21:07+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/10/10/google-reader</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google have launched an online RSS
<a href="http://www.google.com/reader/things/tour">Reader</a>. Like most
developments from Google, this looks very professional and fits in
with their rapidly growing suite of software products. Although I
currently use Thunderbird for reading (a very limited number of) RSS
sources and blogs, the use of a Web based service to manage all my
information sources, accessible from anywhere, is appealing.</p>

<p>I experimented by setting up one source (BBC News) and one thing about
the interface immediately struck me like a thunderbolt !</p>

<p>The use of the 'j' and 'k' keys to move the article list up and
down. It is just like the good old trusty (and much maligned) Unix
editor 'vi'.  Now this may appeal to Unix users but I am not sure
whether the new generation of IE users will make of the 'oh but for
touch typists, it is so much faster' argument.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
