<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: wordpress | Blog In Isolation]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/categories/wordpress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T20:07:32+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy C]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[probably the best blogging platform in the world]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/11/30/probably-the-best-blogging-platform-in-the-world/"/>
    <updated>2005-11-30T05:49:34+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/11/30/probably-the-best-blogging-platform-in-the-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a previous
<a href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/11/29/new-regulus-theme-for-wordpresscom/">article</a>,
I wanted to add a trackback to properly cite an article on Ben
Gillbank's blog about his Regulus theme.</p>

<p>I couldn't find the trackback URL but, as ever, WordPress is doing all
the donkey work for me and now I see my posting does indeed appear as
a comment in Ben's original article.</p>

<p>No manual intervention, head scratching or wasted time. Exactly as it
should be.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[new Regulus theme for WordPress.com]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/11/29/new-regulus-theme-for-wordpresscom/"/>
    <updated>2005-11-29T20:39:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/11/29/new-regulus-theme-for-wordpresscom</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Those nice people at WordPress have opened up WordPress.com to the
masses and added a couple of new
<a href="http://matt.wordpress.com/tag/themes/">themes</a>. I really like the
'<a href="http://www.binarymoon.co.uk/2005/11/regulus-new-wordpress-theme-released/">Regulus</a>'
theme from Ben Gillbanks because it looks clear and uncluttered, the
tag line is displayed and the RSS feeds for the blog and comments are
obvious.</p>

<p>The only polite suggestions for improvement would be to relocate 'Blog
Roll' under the 'Archive' and 'Categories' to let the main body text
occupy more of the screen and for 'Message ssage' to be fixed in the
'Comments' section.</p>

<p>Please don't tell me that bulleted lists appear in bold. They are not.
Apparently, they are just in a different colour. :-) The author is
kindly going to fix this issue in the next release.</p>

<p>So now my blog has a pretty picture of the vast, infinite emptiness of
the universe and 'Blog in Isolation' is reinstated. Very apt.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[thoughts on the Blogger to Wordpress upgrade]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/11/13/thoughts-on-the-blogger-to-wordpress-upgrade/"/>
    <updated>2005-11-13T18:42:20+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/11/13/thoughts-on-the-blogger-to-wordpress-upgrade</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Things I like about Wordpress after a couple of days...
-   The dashboard summary which includes 'Incoming Links', recent posts</p>

<pre><code>and comments at a glance. Wordpress also provides? basic statistics
(hits, entry page, referrer). It looks like the data? is
automatically cleaned of spiders and bots so the figures you get are
more likely to relate to actual human beings. You can also remove
hits incurred as part of administration.
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>Being able to easily and quickly define a hierarchy of categories
and tag your posts. I thought that the RSS feed for an individual
category is really good as it means that Oracle types can choose to
only subscribe to that element of the blog (and ignore football,
music and gadgets).</li>
<li>Categories also helps navigation. If someone wrote a gem of an
article two years ago about Linux, you are more likely to be able to
find it using categories rather than trawling through the complete
blog.</li>
<li>RSS feed for comments.</li>
<li>Clean, quick, intuitive, well designed interface.</li>
<li>The post editor which includes a WYSIWYG preview. I used to dislike
the? fact that the Blogger Preview used a larger font so?
sub-consciously I didn't view it? as the finished article. The
Blogger Preview, Close, Edit, Preview? cycle required a lot of key
clicks and wasted time. The Wordpress preview is precisely that.</li>
<li>Automatic pings to ping-o-matic (and on to 15 services including
Technorati).</li>
<li>The fact that pasting in text from Blogger preserved the hyperlinks.
I am still perplexed as to how that worked.</li>
<li>Posting seems much quicker compared to Blogger. No more waiting and
nervously watching 'This may take a while if you have a large blog'.</li>
<li>Indenting quoted text correctly uses the 'blockquote' tag.</li>
<li>Support for trackbacks and pingbacks as opposed to Blogger's
backlinks.</li>
<li>Support for breaking long posts using 'More'.</li>
<li>The price.</li>
</ul>


<p>Minor things I don't like so much
-   The lack of template editing isn't a big issue for me. If I was that</p>

<pre><code>fussed, I would use wordpress.org and host it myself. Manually
tweaking HTML templates isn't exactly my idea of fun. What I would
really like though is a Template Editor so you can select which
elements (RSS feed, Comments feed, individual Category feeds) appear
on the main page. My Yahoo! provide something similar to select and
arrange content on the home page.
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>The fact the tagline 'Blog in Isolation' does not appear in the Pool
theme.</li>
<li>No automated tool to import from Blogger. I think one exists but is
currently in for repair. My blog was only 30 articles so I
laboriously cut and pasted all my blogger articles (and lost the two
comments).</li>
<li>No support for Technorati tags in the post editor but I think I
prefer using Wordpress categories anyway.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[another change of scene]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/11/13/another-change-of-scene/"/>
    <updated>2005-11-13T02:15:53+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/11/13/another-change-of-scene</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Reader</p>

<p>We had some great times on blogger together but all good things must
come to an end.</p>

<p>I just feel we need a break from each another. I need some time to
think and some personal space (on Wordpress) and there is no other ISP
involved. Please - believe me.</p>

<p>The Web site hits were bubbling up nicely, the feedburner circulation
peaked at 14 and we even had a couple of people referring to and
commenting on this blog.</p>

<p>However, unfortunately my owner's head has been turned by the use of
'categories', an RSS feed for 'Comments', trackback links which he
still doesn't understand and a new, trendy beta version of a blogging
platform used by the Scobleizer (and Eddie Awad) so he has dumped me
in favour of
<a href="http://andyc.wordpress.com/">http://andyc.wordpress.com/</a></p>

<p>Wordpress automatically provides a feed for the new blog from
<a href="http://andyc.wordpress.com/feed/">http://andyc.wordpress.com/feed/</a>
and a separate feed for comments (which is a nice idea) -
<a href="http://andyc.wordpress.com/comments/feed/">http://andyc.wordpress.com/comments/feed/</a></p>

<p>My owner also deleted and recreated the Feedburner feed despite the
dire warnings (he was too stupid to fathom out the fancy
auto-redirection) so
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/AndyC">http://feeds.feedburner.com/AndyC</a>
may or may not still work or you might have to remove and recreate it.</p>

<p>After all we have been through, you still mean a lot to me and I hope
that we can still be good friends.</p>

<p>All my love</p>

<p>The Blogger bytestream that was 'Blog in isolation'</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Winter is the time for migration]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/11/12/winter-is-the-time-for-migration/"/>
    <updated>2005-11-12T03:22:04+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2005/11/12/winter-is-the-time-for-migration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was investigating the bewildering world of trackbacks, pingbacks and
blog comments and found that my existing provider, blogger.com,
supports backlinks (inbound links to a specific article from a Google
search) but not trackbacks.</p>

<p>Then I discovered <a href="http://wordpress.org/">Wordpress.org</a> which is a
blogging tool that supports proper trackbacks, pingbacks (and a whole
lot more besides). Although Wordpress is a freely available OpenSource
PHP based application, I would need to upgrade my current web hosting
to include PHP (for the massive sum of an additional 4GBP per month).</p>

<p>Then I discovered the hosted service
<a href="http://wordpress.com/">Wordpress.com</a> which offers the same
functionality so I registered for an invitation email. A little more
research unearthed the useful fact that the recently released Flock
browser also includes a free Wordpress.com account. I immediately
downloaded Flock and got myself this new, shiny Wordpress blog.</p>

<p>I like the blog editing facilities (you can tag each post in multiple
categories) which may render that tedious task of manually adding
Technorati tags obsolete.</p>

<p>Pros: trackbacks, pingbacks, categories, builtin referrer tracking,
immediate WSIWYG preview, automatic Technorati pings</p>

<p>Cons: no direct access to Web server logs and statistics, need to
manually import existing blog from blogger, centred formatting, need
to burn new feed, lose thousands of readers</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
