<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: uncategorised | Blog In Isolation]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/categories/uncategorised/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T20:07:32+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy C]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[9/11 - The Falling Man]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/12/22/marketing-plan-drupal-7-launch/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-22T12:05:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/12/22/marketing-plan-drupal-7-launch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The date for the long awaited Drupal 7 release has been <a href="">announced</a> as
5 January 2011.</p>

<object width="480" height="385"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/0oBHEvYAJnY?fs=1&amp;hl=en_GB&amp;rel=0"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/0oBHEvYAJnY?fs=1&amp;hl=en_GB&amp;rel=0" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="480" height="385"></embed></object>


<p>Dries should just play this video. Then he should simply read the
following and leave the stage.</p>

<blockquote><p>Straight as an arrow<br/>
 Defect defect<br/>
 Not straight, not so straight<br/>
 Reject reject<br/>
 Towards anti-social<br/>
 Solo solo</p>

<p> Standing on the stairs<br/>
 Cold, cold morning<br/>
 Ghostly image of fear<br/>
 Mayday, mayday<br/>
 Gonna leave this reigon<br/>
 They'll take me with them</p>

<p> Drupal 7</p>

<p> Drupal 7<br/>
 Drupal 7<br/>
 Drupal 7<br/>
 Drupal 7<br/>
 Drupal 7<br/>
 Drupal 7<br/>
 Drupal 7</p></blockquote>

<p>  http://buytaert.net/drupal-7-to-be-released-on-january-5th-with-one-ginormous-party</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[9/11 - The Falling Man]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/12/15/cock-watch-2/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-15T09:36:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/12/15/cock-watch-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Frankly I think the pair deserve each other but some excellent
<a href="http://uk.eurosport.yahoo.com/football/early-doors/article/303175/">quotes</a> from Tevez's agent, Kia Joorabchian, on Garry Cock.</p>

<blockquote><p>‘Garry Cock thinks he's bigger than Carlos Tevez.'</p>

<p>‘Garry Cock has an inflated opinion of himself. I brought him in from
Nike after he begged me to get him a job in football.'</p>

<p>‘I got him a job which paid him more than four times what he was
earning at Nike and he didn't complain about me then but it's all gone
to his head.'</p>

<p>‘Maybe because he played no part in bringing Carlos to the club that's
a problem for him. Maybe he's upset because he didn't have any input.'</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[bang the (ear) drum]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/07/02/bang-the-ear-drum/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-02T11:12:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/07/02/bang-the-ear-drum</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>[ Working title: Torture on a shoestring ]</p>

<p>A couple of weeks ago on a normal, routine Tuesday morning, I did what I
do every morning; showered, prepared for work and cleaned my ears out
with a cotton wool bud. As I went to leave the bathroom, I swung my arms
up and around to put my dressing gown back on for the short trip down
the upstairs landing.</p>

<p>[ This requirement to be modestly covered up follows an unfortunate
incident in April 2009 when my teenage daughter had a sleepover with
three friends staying over. Apparently, one poor girl can not even look
at a Chippolata sausage ever again. Needless to say, I conducted my own
defence and was acquitted. Again. ]</p>

<p>Anyway, as I simulataneously hoisted both arms up to don my long,
flowing, white, silk robe adorned with ‘MUFC - Champions 2008' on the
back, I felt pain. A lot of pain. Searing pain that made me feel quite
dizzy. I paused for breath and suddenly realised I had inadvertently
rammed a cotton wool bud, deep and hard, into my right ear.</p>

<p>It was so painful, I didn't even shout, exclaim or swear. Instinctively,
I reached for my right ear and gingerly extracted the cotton wool bud. I
felt more pain. I clasped my hand over my ear and half expected my palm
to be dripping in blood. Thankfully, there was no blood - just numbing
pain.</p>

<p>I gingerly made my way back to my bedroom and sat down as I felt quite
faint. After a few minutes, the pain subsided slightly to a constant,
painful throb and I was able to get up and get dressed.</p>

<p>I am constantly amazed at the human body's resilience and powers of
natural healing so I just waited for the ear to heal. The next few days
were quite interesting; the feeling was similar to what I would expect
after standing adjacent to a 30 foot Marshall amp stack for the full 3
days of Glastonbury with slight loss of hearing, ringing, dull pain and
various popping noises similar to the sensation you get when descending
in a aircraft.</p>

<p>Eventually, Norma asked why I was popping Nurofen all day every day so I
had to own up. As expected, she took great delight in my agony as she‘d
always claimed ears were self-regulating organs and simply do not need
to be cleaned daily with a blunt instrument which causes more harm than
good. She showed me great sympathy by saying: 'Well, I bet it was
absolutely nothing like child birth.'</p>

<p>I pondered on this for a while and concluded she was right - I had
merely rammed a very small, narrow foreign object into the human body
via a small orifice with great force whereas childbirth consists of
ejecting a natural body out of the human body via a, err, slightly
larger orifice with moderate force. However, I decided it might be
prudent to maintain a dignifed silence (in case she slapped me on the
ear) and the very thought ot childbirth and bodily fluids made me feel
slightly queasy again.</p>

<p>Days passed but the pain and odd sensations didn't so I went to see my
Doctor primarily as I had some concerns about flying in a plane with a
perforated eardrum.</p>

<p>Inevitably, the consulation with my GP was livened up by me pretending
not to hear when she opened up with ‘Now, Mr. Brightside, how can I help
you today ?' and I responded with ‘Sorry - what did you say ?', ‘Pardon'
and ‘Can you speak up a little ? I have a slight problem with my right
ear.'</p>

<p>As I sheepishly confessed to my idiotic, self-inflicted act of
stupidity, the Doctor listened attentively and nodded knowlingly -
'Don't worry Mr. Brightside. I've seen people who've inserted all sorts
of things into all sorts of, err, irregular, places.'</p>

<p>Fair play to the lady GP. She immediately grabbed her menacing ear probe
with the triangular metal end and integrated torchlight and responded
with ‘OK then, let's have a good look in 'ere' and the odd ‘Ooh - what
have we 'ere ?'.</p>

<p>She gently inserted her probe (soft porn SEO keyword search alert) and
promptly reported the ear was too inflamed to see whether the ear drum
was intact or perforated. She reassured me (sort of) by saying the cabin
pressure in a plane wouldn't be an issue if the eardrum was perforated
as the air would simply ‘whistle straight through the hole'.</p>

<p>She then asked me if I had any other specific worries or questions and I
replied ‘Not really - it's mainly the prospect of flying. Oh and I did
want to ask you about the leaking brain fluid…' ‘Brain fluid ?', she
interjected in a serious tone. ‘Yes - when I wake up my pillow has all
this yellow/brown-ish liquid where my head's been resting and my wife,
who is a qualified nurse, told me it was just my 'brain fluid' leaking
out.'</p>

<p>‘Well - with respect, I think your wife might be mistaken or having a
little joke. I'm pretty sure this is just residual fluid from the
inflamed area as the body recovers but I'll prescribe you some
antibiotics which will help clear up the infection.'</p>

<p>The ear is now almost completely healed. I have thrown away the bumper
pack of 240 ear buds although my right earbud now keeps falling out on
when I listen to music on the train.</p>

<p>The memory of the ‘ear drum' incident is now receding but I'm pretty
sure intelligence agencies and the military could use this technique to
produce a cheaper and much more efficient form of torture.
<a href="http://davidmarsden.info/waterboarding-on-the-nhs">Waterboarding</a> is well publicised and effective but can get very
messy and is very wasteful of a precious natural resource.</p>

<p>Imagine, in the next James Bond film, the baddie enters the
interrogation cell armed - not with a large belt or a car battery and
two electrical diodes - but simply brandishing a single cotton wool bud.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[turbulence ahead]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/06/23/turbulence-ahead/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-23T09:38:55+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/06/23/turbulence-ahead</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am about to embark on migrating this blog from WordPress to
Django-Mingus because I simply can't stand the WordPress 'Compose Post'
interface (if you can call it that).</p>

<p>This exciting move comes less than two weeks after I spotaneously
decided to ditch Habari after the lack of a functional 'Auto-Save'
plugin caused me to lose 17 minutes work.</p>

<p>You may say 'I'm reading this in my preferred RSS reader so please don't
bother me with such minutiae'.</p>

<p>However, when I migrated from Habari to WordPress a month ago, I flooded
you both with my most recent posts duplicated so this is just prior
warning that similar oddness may well occur as I endeavour to hook up
the new blog feed to FeedBurner.</p>

<p>This may or may not signal a period of blog hopping and I'd like to say
this <del>will</del> may trigger a series of interesting posts about which
blogging platforms I considered and discarded and top tips on planning
and executing an efficient blog migration.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wayne Rooney's World Cup diary]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/06/08/wayne-rooneys-world-cup-diary-1/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-08T10:31:53+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nbrightside.com/blog/2010/06/08/wayne-rooneys-world-cup-diary-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tuesday 1 June</p>

<p>Mr.  Capello announces the  final squad  of 23  players for  the World
Cup. There was the odd surprise  and some devastated players as we say
a tearful farewell to Huddza, Johnno, the Scott-Meister, Les (Dawson),
Dazza The  Bender, Walcottza and the  quiet one (I think  his name was
Leighton Baines).</p>

<p>Saturday 5 June</p>

<p>Rio and Heskey have a argument over Wii Tennis that carries over into
a training match. After winning a defensive header, Rio tells Heskey
'Dunno why you're still here. I've scored more international goals
than you.' Heskey retaliates by sliding in by the corner flag and
sitting on Rio's left knee.</p>

<p>Sunday 6 June</p>

<p>Rio has done medial ligaments and Mr. Capello is very cross. He had
put his name down for the Wii Tennis tournament and no-one told him
when he was on. Mr. Baldini reads the riot act and Rio goes to
hospital.</p>

<p>Mr. Ferguson rings me and is screaming so loud I have to hold the
receiver away from my sunburnt ear. He wants me to get Emile Heskey to
sit on me so I can miss the World Cup and get sent home to Manchester.</p>

<p>Monday 7 June</p>

<p>Crisis meeting mainly for the defenders but we all have to go which is
a shame as I was beating Joe Hart 79-71 in a Noughts and Crosses
marathon session in the hotel lobby.</p>

<p>A young fair haired lad called Dawson turns up. No-one really knows
who is he or why he's here.  I think he might be an undercover
reporter or Joe Cole's agent. Anyway, Mr. Baldini says he is replacing
Rio in the Wii Tennis tournament.</p>

<p>Mr.  Capello wants to sort out the communication between the back four
and the rest of the team. Rio used to call me 'Wazza', JT 'Tezza',
Stevie G 'Gezza' etc so it was all quite easy. However, the young fair
haired lad can't learn all these nicknames in time. Mr. Capello wants
us to use 'Senor Rooney' but this takes too long. Baldini suggests
shortening this to 'Rooney' which wins 20-5 in a vote.</p>

<p>After 37 minutes, plunged in silent, deep thought, Sean
Wright-Phillips says something: "What about Joe Cole and Ashley Cole ?
They will now both be called 'Cole'."</p>

<p>Mr.  Capello is annoyed at this interruption as dinner is nearly ready
and he asked for his favourite - Spaghetti Hoops - tonight so he
quickly ends the discussion: 'Right - Ashley will be '55 grand' and
Senor Cole will be 'Cole'.</p>

<p>Gareth Barry says that 'Cole' sounds a little but like 'Goal'
but Mr. Baldini says that won't be a problem.</p>

<p>Tuesday 8 June</p>

<p>Papers giving me a lot of stick for reckless challenges, getting
booked and telling a referee to 'Feck Off' in a friendly against John
Terry's All Gold Platinum All Stars. I am summoned to a meeting with
Mr. Capello and the new captain Steve Gerrard. David Beckham is also
present - his main role was to coach Theo - but now he just has to
check no-one is wearing flip-flops and keep Rio's spirits up.</p>

<p>Have a chat with Steve Gerrard and Jamie Carragher by the pool. They
are a little hard to understand (even for me) but they are in high
spirits. Steve reckons we can go all the way and win it this time. He
keeps saying 'Listen, eh - la. Good things come in threes. Rio's
injury gave me the captaincy. Rafa was sacked by Liverpool so this
must mean we are going to win it and Stevie Me will lift the World
Cup, instantly treble my value and get my dream move to Chelsea, sorry
Real Madrid.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
